Chapter 32: Descendants Pt IV, Severus Snape

All my thanks to Jared, Joe, and Kuilin, who beta-ed this chapter.

10:10 am, June 28th, 1993

After proper use of memory charms and five turns of his Time-Turner, Lucius was put back into the sewer, leaving Salazar all to himself.

From extensive exploration of Giuliani's mind, Salazar saw that Giuliani had talked to portraits on various occasions, and the portraits seemed to respond in a reasonable way. The portraits in Salazar's time could only enunciate very simple sentences, or carry out simple tasks such as opening doors only to those that knew certain passwords. It seemed that later wizards had developed better portrait techniques. Since Nagini mentioned nothing of it, it must be another non-Interdicted yet interesting development. With any luck, Salazar could grab a portrait that could speak both Latin and the current vernacular, and use it as a translator.

Salazar disillusioned himself again, and walked into the corridors. The first portrait he saw was a drawing of two witches in extravagant garments, the collars of which were wider than their shoulders. The witches were whispering to each other in a language resembling French, and constantly looking around in alert.

-So the portraits are indeed much better these days.

Salazar pointed his wand to the frame of the portrait, and felt the delicate magic and the link of it with Hogwarts. It seemed that all portraits were made to obey orders from the current headmaster or headmistress of Hogwarts, which made things very convenient for Salazar. With a few twists similar to what Salazar had already done to the house-elves before he entered the Mirror, all the portraits in Hogwarts would obey Salazar first, and then the current headmaster and headmistress only if Salazar had not ordered them otherwise.

Salazar had been tempted to get a portrait of a passed headmaster or headmistress for their superior knowledge, but that was too obvious, so he settled for a portrait hanging in a deserted corner. The eccentric wizard depicted in the portrait was Roderick Plumpton, who had been a seeker in the ridiculous game nowadays called "Quidditch", a painter later in life, and died from old age four years ago.

As Plumpton explained, the use of someone's willingly donated blood and memory before they died, alongside with some special techniques, could make portraits behave like the persons depicted in them. The original aim of wizarding painters was to use the advanced portraits to bypass the Interdict of Merlin, but that was unsuccessful.

With the help from Plumpton, Salazar knew that the younger Tom Riddle who called himself "Harry Potter" wanted to use the Mirror to lock the current out-and-running adult Tom Riddle and all his horcruxes in Time. "Harry Potter" had told Severus and the "Auror" named Moody, that the ritual would require himself to be sacrificed, and be locked in Time as well. "Harry Potter" asked Severus and Moody's help in setting up this magic and then being obliviated, to which both men agreed.

What Salazar heard was quite confusing: what is this younger Riddle actually planning to do? What he has planned can indeed lock all Riddles up - well, if I haven't cleaned the dirt from Rowena's Diadem, I can lock all Tom Riddles in Time now. But why would he do it? Does he really consider himself a hero like Godric? Or maybe this Plumpton is such an idiot that he completely mistranslated things.

Then, in private, "Harry Potter" told the girl emanating the smell of unicorn that since he was indeed another Tom Riddle, once the magic of the Mirror was triggered, he would also be locked in Time. This girl named "Hermione Granger" and little Draco should lead human beings to advance magic and something called "science" for the next several hundred years, conquer other galaxies, evacuate something called the "Milky Way Galaxy", then release all Tom Riddles from the Mirror. At that time, she should save this "Harry Potter" and the obliviated Tom Riddle in the form of a ring, then -

The younger Tom Riddle's words were cut off at this point, maybe because he literally couldn't say what would happen in the next step. However, Salazar could guess: the younger Tom Riddle is implying that the Granger girl should destroy the "Milky Way Galaxy", and in this way, the Prophecy that this Tom Riddle would destroy the world would be fulfilled in the best possible way.

Salazar ignored the various sounds made by the Granger girl, and mulled over the younger Tom Riddle's statement for quite some time. When he finally reached a passable answer for the motive of this particular Tom Riddle, it was just as crazy as the previous possibilities Salazar had thought of: this Riddle has found the many horcruxes and the many versions of "Tom Riddle" annoying, or he thought his many horcruxes might lead to world destruction. However, some of the horcruxes were so well-hidden that even he himself can't find them. The only way that he could think of to get rid of all other Tom Riddles was to blast the whole earth plus nearby stars.

Needless to say, Salazar had quite a headache absorbing this new information. However, if there was a possibility to lock all the Riddles in Time for a while, Lord Slytherin would surely help, even if that meant delaying the formulation of his plot to use the Stone for a few days.

In the Headmistress' Office, the younger Tom Riddle showed Severus the Stutterer and Alastor "Mad-Eye" Moody some notes from the Muggle-loving fool Albus Dumbledore, and some older notes from his Line of Merlin Unbroken heritage, then asked them if they could figure out the details of how to lock someone in Time, and how to control the process remotely.

Naturally, Lord Slytherin took this chance to duplicate all the notes that he could lay his hands on, examined the notes in an empty classroom nearby, and kept a keen ear on the Headmistress' office. In case they couldn't work out the details after a while, Salazar wouldn't mind secretly offering them some hints.

Luckily for Salazar, most notes passed down from the holders of Line of Merlin Unbroken before Karen Dutton, the stupid witch who chose Dumbledore as her successor, were written in Greek, Latin, and occasional ancient Runes and Hebrew, all of which Salazar could understand pretty well.

In all the notes left by Merlin himself, Salazar could only find one piece of half-torn paper that contained something related to the mass-sacrificial ritual that Godric and Lucius warned him about. The letters on it were almost illegible scratches, and Salazar could only decipher "atomos", "lux", "stella", and "mors", the last of which was written quite a number of times, as if the writer was in great agony and anxiety.

-Atom, light, stars, and death. What do they mean? Death would be the result, atom would be the things sacrificed, and Lucius mentioned something about "why the stars shine"... But why? How?

Although common sense told Salazar that since the ritual-weapon had not destroyed the world during the past fifty years, it was unlikely to destroy the world in the next few days, Salazar's mind was still preoccupied by it, and even the rest of Merlin's notes that contained hints of a number of powerful spells and rituals had lost their attraction to Salazar at this moment.

-Lucius told me that Severus knew more about the weapon, and Severus might also have means to lay his hands on the weapon. Therefore, I need to liberate Severus from his current task on figuring out how to use the Mirror soon.

From Plumpton's translation, it seemed that Moody and Severus spent almost a day, pondering on how to communicate one's wishes with the Mirror, before the younger Tom Riddle finally spoke up.

"Ponite occlumency obice, suspicor." Plumpton translated the younger Tom Riddle's words.

Salazar sighed inwardly.

-If Tom Riddle is going to give information as simple as "drop your occlumency barrier" at this rate, I may need to wait until the next year for anything to really happen.

Salazar pointed his wand toward the general direction of the headmistress' office, and cast, "Siticulos."

The simple Siticulos spell that Salazar learnt from Constantinople was quite harmless by itself, and it did nothing except making people in that general direction thirsty. However, if it was cast by several powerful wizards with all their strength, it would lead to the entire enemy army consume much more water than planned, and thus it was a very powerful spell while fighting in arid areas such as Egypt. In this case, the spell would only lead to the inconspicuous need for the loo within one or two few hours.

Salazar pointed his wand to the wall of the empty classroom, and connected himself to the wards. He located the private toilet attached to the headmistress' office, which was only added long after the conjuration of Hogwarts, and made some small adjustment in sound transmission of the toilet. Salazar didn't quite understand the need for "privacy" instead of socialization while using the toilet or the bathroom, but since this new trend worked to his advantage at this time, he wasn't going to complain.

Then, the old lord waited patiently while flipping through the notes left by the holders of Line of Merlin Unbroken, looking for anything related to "atomos", "lux", and "stella", while keeping an ear on the headmistress' office.

Approximately one hour later, the younger Tom Riddle needed to use the toilet. Both Severus and Moody went into the toilet together with the "Boy-Who-Lived", and checked the toilet thoroughly. Unfortunately for them, the modifications Salazar did was indeed part of the castle, and the Eye of Vance had a limit for how many walls it could see pass through.

Salazar approved the companion of others while in potential danger in principle, -that was, if it was not in the way of his plot.

-Didn't Plumpton say current population need "privacy"? Do I need to make up a new plot?

Luckily, Severus and Moody soon left the toilet, and left the younger Tom Riddle all to himself. A while later, the younger Riddle left the toilet, and Severus entered.

Salazar carefully applied a white-blue shield of Protego Vitamaxima in the innermost circle, an invisible single-sided silencing charm in the second circle, another invisible single-sided smell concealing charm in the third circle, and a Circaduplucem to the outmost circle. Before entering the Mirror, Salazar used to apply one spell of his own creation that served both as protection and concealment before Apparation; now, with the invention of Protego Vitamaxima, he wouldn't trust any lesser protection spells, yet he didn't have time to create a new combinatorial spell. Although Salazar was reluctant to admit it, the fact was, applying all four separate spells in a row was a bit stretching for the Greatest of Hogwarts Four.

Salazar checked the new combination of shield and concealment again, and apparated into the headmistress' large bathroom while the sound of toilet flushing began.

To Salazar's both delight and annoyment, the second he landed in the bathroom, the black-haired wizard who was reaching for the faucet suddenly had his wand in hand, and cursed toward the general direction of where Salazar landed: "Ava -"

Salazar's stunning hex smashed through the faint blue shield just started to spring out from some trinket attached to Severus' robes, and rendered the black-haired wizard completely immobile.

Just as Salazar grabbed Severus' wrist and prepared to apparate again, another version of a slightly confused looking Severus appeared from nowhere.

"Go quickly," Salazar heard the slightly strange sound of himself hissing.

Lord Slytherin didn't need more cues, for he knew it was hard even for himself to produce a believable illusion for the holder of Eye of Vance for a prolonged period of time.

When Salazar apparated back to the empty classroom, he didn't take off the illusions immediately, for he knew he was sweating and slightly panting from the succession of protection and illusion spells, the two apparitions, and the powerful stunning hex. For some reason, Salazar didn't want his descendant to see it, even if he knew that Severus would be obliviated afterwards.

-For the sake of Atlantis, I could do this type of thing five times in a row and still had energy for a dance merely ten years ago, - oh, well, ten years ago for me anyway. And now, my bones and joints start to protest, and my heart is pounding so fast.

The aged Lord Slytherin wiped his forehead, composed his breathing, and sized Severus the Stutterer up and down.

The black-haired wizard still had horrified looks frozen on his yellowish face; his black tunneling eyes that resembled Salazar's in his younger years were calculating, maybe because he knew that he would be returned to the very toilet, apparently unharmed; his shoulder-length hair was oily and unkempt, which suited Salazar's taste better than the overtly looked-after white blonde hair of the Malfoys; his black robes were as expensive looking as Lucius', yet dirt and dried moth marred the elegancy of the garments - from his previous search in the tunnels, probably; his fingernails were dry and cracking, and he still held his black wand firmly in his right hand.

Salazar cancelled the concealments, and showed himself in front of Severus. He accioed Severus' wand and pouch without a word or any wand movements, for the appearance of omnipotence was important for the smooth continuation of the conversation to come.

"Greetingss, Sseveruss, my desscendant. Nicce triess for calling for the dirty creaturess." Salazar hissed.

The horrifying apprehension and confusion in Severus' eyes brought Salazar a smirk, then his smirk froze slightly: Severus isn't thinking that I am Tom Riddle, and I am his true father, is he?

With the slight headache that associated with Tom Riddles, the aged lord continued, "I am Ssalazar Sslytherin, the Greatesst of Hogwartss Four. I mean you no harm. "

Confusion, disbelief, and relief flashed through Severus' eyes, then everything was replaced by the emptiness of occlumency.

Salazar had considered trying legilimency on Severus, but decided against it, for the possible failure might infringe his appearance of omnipotence - mental defense is just too simple as comparing to offense, and Tom Riddle wouldn't trust someone without a perfect occlumency barrier for any important secret task.

Since Severus might have figured out that Salazar was the hand behind Lucius' "invention" of Protego Vitamaxima among other things by this point, Salazar did not give Severus the chance to show off his cunning. "And yess, I ssummoned the ssnakess to sschool, killed man-eating sspiderss, and had an interesting converssation with Luciuss."

-But then, Lucius told Severus everything without considering the consequences. Was Lucius deceived of the level of friendship between them by Severus; or did Lucius do this on purpose, for he noticed something was wrong with him, and he wanted people to know, and wanted Severus to feel guilty about revealing it? Hmm. With descendants like this, one may never have a dull moment in life.

"Did you descend from the Malfoy line, or the Gaunt line?" Salazar asked casually, for making Severus too nervous or hostile would be bad for later conversation.

After Salazar waved his hand, Severus the Stutterer spoke slowly, "Ak-cording to Luciuss, I am hiss v-fourth k-cousin, and fiv-fth cousin oncce l-removed,."

There was some strangeness in the way that Severus answered his question, and with Severus' previous reaction when he heard that he was Salazar's descendant…

-Is Severus a bastard or orphan who doesn't know his true parentage?

Salazar silently hoped that Severus wasn't really Tom Riddle's son, for he could deal with the possibility that Severus was Lucius' illegitimate brother, but Salazar didn't want any family drama involving the very descendant that he wanted to lock in Time.

Salazar decided to skip the cunning small talks that might lead to more headache, asked the question that he cared about most. "What do you know about the weapon that invokess the ritual which ssacrificess atomonss or masss, and caussess huge exxplosions?"

Salazar might have seen true confusion and the shock flashed passed Severus' eyes. However, these might just be Severus' covers, since although you couldn't tell lies in Parseltongue, there was no rule about your expressions.

Then, the black-haired wizard spoke slowly, "Not ssure j-you are … to know."

Salazar frowned upon the answer. Salazar knew he should be careful with such rituals, but Lucius had said some of his knowledge came from a "paper" distributed by some wizards in one of the new continents, and it didn't sound that well-kept -

"Luciuss told me about paper distributed by - " Salazar changed to the vernacular he yet to learn, and mimicked Lucius' pronunciation, "Amirikan", then turned back to Parseltongue. "It hass written much about the ssecretss."

Severus' face twitched slightly, his breath became a bit uneven. After a while, Severus slowly began, "Do not get near d-thesse v-weaponss. P-Powerful wizardss may l-render -" Severus searched for words, then said. "A lot ov-f Muggle dew-vicess invented in the passt one hun-dred j-yearss or sso broken. Thiss type of v-weapon can be more dangel-rouss if broken. Sseven yearss ago, ssomev-where in Easstern Eul-Europe, more d-than one hun-dred thousand … people have to be ew-evacuated becausse ssomething like that b-broke."

Salazar nodded slowly, and then realized why Severus was reluctant to reveal information about the ritual-weapon. "I have no intention to usse or own such weaponss, only to take them away from unworthy wielderss, Muggle and wizardss alike. And before I can rid the world of ssuch danger, I have no intention to antagonize Muggle governmentss or groupss that wield the horrible ritual weaponss by any meanss, ssuch ass hurting Muggless."

Severus opened his mouth, then paused. He regarded Salazar carefully, and asked, "Muggle-b-bornss?"

Those dirty illiterate creatures irked Salazar greatly, and he always thought the mudbloods should never be allowed to learn magic. However, Severus did raise a valid point: hurting mudbloods may lead to retaliations from Muggles. By the way, he called them "Muggleborns", like the good and great Lord Gryffindor did. Hmm -

"I sshall not hurt mudbloodss or Muggless unlesss by not doing sso may hurt mysself or Hogwartss." Salazar promised. "And I have no intention to lead to the desstruction of the world."

From Severus' silent mouth movements, Salazar guessed the black-haired wizard might have cursed Lucius. Then the black-haired stutterer said, "The Girl-Who-l-Revived, hass uni-corn blood insside, bl-bringss good luck v-while alive. Do not v-want to imagine v-what would happen if she d-diess. Her pal-parentss are ssquibss."

-Ah, when there is a prophecy that a version of you might bring an end to the world, keep a living luck maximizer around you. Tom Riddle is surely cunning, and he is capable of creating great disasters if things do not go his way - in case the mudblood girl named "Hermione Granger" dies, the retribution from the Universe might really destroy the world. And that's why Severus brought out the topic on mudbloods.

The grim prospect that Lord Slytherin the famous blood purist might be forced into protecting a mudblood girl irked the aged lord greatly, yet he knew better than to challenge the Universe. With an inward sigh and another note to punish all the Tom Riddles with creative methods, Salazar promised reluctantly, "I shall not hurt the girl with unicorn blood, and shall protect her if it iss necesssary."

Noticing that Severus seemed a bit relaxed after hearing this, Salazar had a brief impulse to punish the stutterer for delivering the blackmail sent by Tom Riddle to the entire world, but he held himself better than that, for he knew that Severus did the right thing as to warn him of the things that might lead to great disaster, such as hurting the mudblood girl, or getting near to the ritual-weapons without understanding them first.

"Any other dangerss that I should be aware of?" Salazar hissed.

Severus frowned, then answered, "The Sstone d-that makess transsv-figuration permanent. The Sstone can be used in dan-dangerous v-wayss . For v-what iss worsse, the Boy-Who-Lived ov-offered the sservice of the Sstone to every-one a j-year ago. Many pov-powerful wizardss, gl-groupss, and nationss dessire the Sstone all for … d-themsselvess. World v-warss might sstart."

Salazar nodded to the information that he had already inferred from the various times that the Hogwarts wards were triggered by outside wizards, and the Giuliani guy that he had killed. "I have a plan to deal with that."

Salazar's plan was to awe the powerful lords in the world into submission, as Merlin did, and to proclaim Hogwarts and the Stone of Permanency as his. Although, due to the utter stupidity of the younger Tom Riddle, Salazar might not be able to deprive the use of the Stone from wizards all over the world, for that would definitely lead to a world war, and even the combined forces of the Hogwarts Four at the height of their powers might not be enough to defend Hogwarts from the combined forces from all the wizards in the world, not to mention some might have access to the ritual-weapon.

However, before Salazar could execute his plan, he needed to regain his youth first. And for that part, Salazar might need a living person's help, preferably a Parselmouth. Salazar only knew four possible Parselmouths, including Tom Riddle, Severus, Lucius, and Draco. Out of these four, Tom Riddle was his enemy, Lucius was held as a political prisoner, Draco was too young, therefore, Severus was the most convenient option. That was, before Salazar found other Parselmouths.

"Who do you know are Parsselmouthss?" Salazar asked.

Severus hesitated.

Salazar gave an impatient hiss. "Any danger in thiss ass well?"

"Not s-sure if dan-dangerouss." Severus answered reluctantly. "Can n-name ssome. A-Albuss, v-former sschool-masster, iss one, but he iss ... locked in Time. Bartimuss-" Severus changed into vernacular to say "Crouch", then back to Parseltongue, "Might be one, but he v-went cl-crazy when hiss only sson died." Then he paused.

-Wait, the Muggle-loving fool is a descendant of mine as well? What a delight! Now that I have one descendant who possibly handed the world-ending ritual to Muggles, and one descendant who has a hobby of splitting himself up, fighting himself, and possibly ending the world.

-By the way, Severus isn't providing any useful information by naming one person who was locked in Time and another who went crazy. What is he hiding?

-Ah, the fact that the younger Tom Riddle is a Parselmouth, because Severus still thinks the "boy" is some great figure to be protected, and he is afraid that I might utilize the "boy" for something and causes great danger to the world.

Salazar hissed. "I already knew the one that current wizards call 'the Boy-Who-Lived' and the Malfoyss are Parsselmouthss."

Severus paused, his eyes might became a little more empty, and then he said, "I j-just know one m-more P-Parsselmouth, the Dark Lord -" In vernacular, Severus said the name, "Tom Riddle", then supplemented in Parseltongue, "No idea v-where he iss. He iss very dan-dangerouss."

Salazar nodded to the disappointing news that there were only such a limited number of Parselmouths nowadays, and Severus seemed to be the only one available for the task of helping Salazar to regain his youth.

-Well, Severus isn't a bad choice, actually. His magical power is mediocre, but that level of magic is considered "powerful" per current standards. The "Auror" named Moody only has the same level of magic as Severus does, yet he was entrusted by the young Riddle to guard the Stone, and many enemies of Hogwarts have apparently failed to challenge Moody's wards. Moreover, Severus is discrete, cunning, and interesting. As a bonus, Severus knows quite something about the powerful ritual weapon, and maybe somewhat how the current Muggle society. Therefore, Severus is about as good as I can get as a helper. However, I need to know what leverage I can use on him, if he is to be trusted, and how to convince him to go along with my plan.

-Severus is obviously a sane man who doesn't want the world to end, so maybe I can convince him that helping me would help the world. However, most people cannot be easily motivated by such grandeur pursuits if going down such paths may require them to do something as simple as changing their traveling methods from broomstick to flying carpets. Severus seems to be better than that, but I'd better not take the risk before I know him better. Money is a common tools to motivate people, but since Severus used the Stone for several hours during that interesting night, I guess he already has plenty of gold. Personal ambition, then. I hope the ex-Head of my House has the ambition to become a really powerful wizard.

"What languagess can you sspeak?" Salazar asked, for learning as many ancient language as you could was a standard requirement for anyone who was serious in power since the Interdict of Merlin.

"English, F-French, Old English, Old Fl-French, Latin, Ancient Gl-Greek, Runess, Hebrew, P-Parsseltongue, ssome Hiel-Hieroglyph, ssome Old German, and I am learn-learning Sspanish and - " Severus changed into vernacular, "Russian."

-Twelve besides the current English and Parseltongue, acceptable. It seems that Severus has been determined to gain more power for quite some time, for you do not learn a dozen languages in a short time. He should at least add Aramaic, Arabic, Cuneiform, Persian, and Sanskrit to his list, though. On a second thought, he - and I - should also learn Chinese and the language called "Jaepeneese", for Tom Riddle has gained much knowledge over there.

-Severus' intelligence and cunning are already tested, so he is an acceptable helper.

The ancient lord hissed. "If you agree to help me to regain youth ssecretly, I would help you to defeat my desscendent from the Gaunt line, the persson you call the Dark Lord."

Obviously, Salazar didn't bother to mention the fact that he would defeat the Tom Riddles whether Severus chose to cooperate or not.

The black-haired man's face turned grey, then hissed as if he was facing his own death. "I sshall not help you ssteal or l-rob the Sstone, for d-that may lead to v-world desstruction."

The old wizard suppressed his annoyance, and hissed: "Have no plan to ssteal or rob the Sstone, jusst to usse it ass sso many otherss from the entire world have."

-Well, of course, after I have awed all the powerful wizards in the world into submission, I plan to publicly claim the Stone as my own. But before that, I can be temporarily content at going back to my early thirties.

Severus eyed Salazar with great suspicion, and asked: "I am a P-Parsselmouth, sso iss d-the Boy-v-Who-Lived. Kv-Quicker if you reveal yoursself in fl-front of him and assk. V-Why me?"

-Because the so-called "the Boy-Who-Lived" is Tom Riddle, you fool!

"Ass Luciuss and you have said, too much danger in and around him." Salazar carefully chose what he could say without revealing the boy's true identity, for as long as the younger Tom Riddle were to be confident that he was under a perfect cover of a young hero, he must act the part of hero in front of other's eyes, and made the world safer. "No plan to tilt world balance toward danger in any way or form. Shall not explain in more detailss, for that might be dangerouss."

Though Severus didn't seem to be convinced by this answer, he chose to give up on this question, and asked another. "How do you l-live for sso long? V-Why hass nobody heard of j-you for sso long?"

-Does Severus suspect me of using some stupid methods such as horcrux to achieve longevity? Yeah, and Godric and I started the rumor. Does he blame his own possible misfortune on me? Perhaps this one isn't as sharp as Lucius, because Lucius didn't ask - nah, Lucius was too afraid of his own neck back then, yet Severus is quite sure he will be returned to that bathroom in the future. And after all, nobody has ever mimicked Lord Slytherin's wise move in more than nine hundred years.

With a hint of gloat, Salazar answered his descendant's question: "The Mirror."

Severus the Stutterer opened his mouth, then looked as if he wanted to hit himself with a hammer. Slowly, and some cloud of renewed suspicion rose up in his black eyes. "V-Would you help uss in our ka...current tassk v-with the Mirror?"

-Oh, well, Severus probably has correctly deduced that I am inclined to help him locking up all Tom Riddles. For the sake of Atlantis, I can hardly decide which kind of showing-off is more annoying: the Malfoys' extravagance, or Severus' cleverness! Yet, Godric had often accused me of gloating…

Salazar struggled between the roles of an annoyed lord and a doting grandfather, and silently admitted to himself that his judgement might have been compromised by the softness in his old age. With a note that he needed to regain his youth sooner, Salazar hissed: "If you cooperate with me, I shall leave you hintss on that ssubject ass well."

Severus' eyes flickered, and then promised: "I v-will co-cooperate, but I le-retain right to sstop, in casse I ssee danger of v-world de-desstruction in d-doing sso. I v-will tell you the rea...reason if I can."

That sounded reasonable to Lord Slytherin. The old lord hissed: "You can only hide information from me under the circumsstance that by telling me sso, the very act may endanger the world. If you accept, then deal. "

Severus considered, and hissed. "Deal."

Note: In canon, Dumbledore could speak more than a hundred languages, and Crouch, Sr. could speak more than two hundred. This certainly makes a lot of sense in a world with the Interdict of Merlin where one of the greatest sources of power is to read ancient text and to guess the secrets buried behind. However, if anyone who is serious to gain power has to learn that many languages, a great many powerful lords might be intellectually exhausted afterwards, and have no energy to think about something such as "magical Enlightenment". Think about Harry, if he were to be brought up by a distinguished magical scholar, then probably he has to learn Old English, Old French, Latin and Greek as a start, and Hebrew and Runes as a first-step supplement, with Hieroglyph and Arabic in the waiting, etc. By the end of the day, I wonder if Harry would ever have the time or mental capacity to read any scientific literature even when they are put in front of him.

Chapter 33: Classes Pt I, Food Safety

All my thanks to Kuilin, my dear beta.

RIP, Alan Rickman. I hope someone has made a Version 3.0 Horcrux for you, so that we can still hear your unmistakable voices and watch your excellent performances after we figure out how to make a Stone.

Chapter 33.

11:59 am, July 7th, 1993

"Time is up, turn in your papers now." Severus knocked on the blackboard in the small classroom, and waved his wand.

Harry raised his head as his quiz drifted toward the ex-Potions master, looked around, finding both Draco and Hermione were looking nervously at Severus. While Severus started flipping through their quizes, and marking things down quickly, Harry had a surreal feeling about his life in general.

After several days of intensive saving-the-world activities and setting up the Mirror so that it would lock up all the Tom Riddles upon command or the lack of certain commands, the Boy-Who-Lived, the Girl-Who-Revived and, in Mad-Eye's words - the "Malfoy brat who should never be here", were back as students again. From Harry's own life experience, maybe the cartoonists weren't completely making things up when they depicted student superheroes who had to save the world on a regular basis and to worry about their homework at the same time.

-At least I don't have to hide the fact that I am the superhero from everyone, and the important people around me understand that.

Harry moved his eyes away from the ex-Potions master, and pondered again on the dilemma that he had been circling at the back of his mind since he was in the dark mode four days ago: should I let Severus revive the real Quirrell? Quirrell might have some information on the whereabouts of Voldemort, not to mention some of his secret powers. The real danger of this matter is that if we choose to do so, we need to keep this thing in complete secrecy. Mad-Eye had offered one of his fake identities to me when he thought that I needed the identity myself, the identity was "somewhat plausible" by Mad-Eye's standards, and he had gone to double check it today. Yesterday, Severus - who no longer remembered it now - had said that he could construct a new revival altar in about two weeks, if he could use the Stone to duplicate some of the leftover magical materials at hand, and his altar in the United States is still usable. Therefore, maybe it is time that I talk to Hermione about this, and ask for her opinion. Well, for potential political implications, I need to talk to Draco as well, and maybe obliviate him later.

Before Harry had weighed out the benefits and shortcomings of a new altar in Britain at some location that Mad-Eye deemed "having some semblance of safety" versus the one in Nevada, Severus had finished grading their quizes and handing back them to the three students. Harry got a ninety-four out of one hundred, and some quick glances told Harry that Hermione got one hundred points while Draco got ninety-one. Harry looked at his paper again, and found that he misspelt the name of a commonly used food poison, and he had omitted a step in the making of the animagus meditation potion, which could render the drinker having a much harder time - or maybe never - in turning back to human form, and Severus had commented that Harry had "an excellent killer's instinct even in mistakes".

The lunch time also turned out to be a quiz time, simply because one of that day's subjects had been various ways that your enemy might sabotage you by food and drinks.

That morning, Minerva first had given a lecture on the theory of animagus transformation, which Harry had already learned by heart.

Then, Mad-Eye had given a two-hour lecture about charms and transfigurations that could be used on the things that went into your stomach, which only covered "the bare minimum of what a stupid criminal would use". As it turned out, Harry's ideas about putting transfigured sulfuric acid into the enemy's teacup wasn't that unique - the story of the criminal who transfigured gold into wine was covered during the very first transfiguration lecture after all. While talking about transfiguration, Mad-Eye had sneered, "Every so often, there is some chap who thinks that he is the only who listened in the first transfiguration class, and comes up with some fancy stuff to transfigure, puff."

Therefore, when house-elves brought them three large trays of food, the real quiz started.

With a hint of smirk, Severus said: "Label all the items that you think are unfit for consumption and why. For the items that you can't name a reason for refusal within twenty minutes, you would later swallow them in front of everyone - rest assured, nothing lethal within fifteen minutes. I sspoke truth, as Mr. Potter could w-verify."

Severus looked at Harry pointedly, and Harry translated the last part Severus said to human language for his friends. Then, Severus conjured magical curtains to block the view so that none of the students could see or hear what others were doing, and a ticking countdown clock showed up in front of Harry - which Harry suspected was actually there to create pressure, instead of showing the time left.

Harry carefully applied an air-refreshing charm on himself, and began testing. He glanced at the delicious-looking steak, fried pork sirloin, stewed diricawl meat, vegetables, chocolate cake, apple pie and pumpkin juice among other items, and couldn't help but began to wonder if Severus and Mad-Eye wanted the three of them to ever enjoy meals again.

About a year ago, Mad-Eye had already given Harry a number of magical trinkets that could detect "certain standard methods only fools would use", and Severus had given them more magical items with similar purpose today. Harry first tested all the food with Mad-Eye's detectors, and no alarm was triggered.

-Well, of course, Mad-Eye and Severus would be more creative than that.

Before Harry's hand touched the magical items Severus gave him today, he stopped, and realized that he should make sure those items actually performed their claimed functions, and didn't have any other functions added - such as being a secret portkey or something.

-Or, maybe the touch of such an item with certain things in the food would have some interesting effects.

-Oh, this is going to be interesting.

Nineteen minutes later, Harry was facing a glass of water and two slices of bread that he couldn't find any magical or non-magical reason to reject - he even measured the density of water, and found nothing irregular. Slytherin commented sarcastically: Bread and water, how pristine! Should we ask for some salt?

As the time on the countdown clock turned to zero, the magical curtains and the clocks disappeared.

From the smirk on Severus' face, Harry was pretty sure that at least one of them would show some very entertaining effects after consuming - Harry glanced at the chocolate eggplant in front of Hermione, and the glass of pumpkin juice in front of Draco.

Harry hoped that he wasn't going to be the clown within the next several minutes. A corner at the back of Harry's mind secretly commented: Look at the smirk on your servant's face. I wonder if he were to serve -

Harry told that corner of himself to shut up, and picked up the glass when Severus looked at him first. With some determination, Harry allowed a small amount of water to enter his mouth, and he immediately spat out the bitter-tasting liquid.

Before asking what was in that liquid or calling for help, Harry pointed his wand to his mouth, and mumbled, "Aguamenti." As Harry began to wash his mouth to get rid of any residue liquid, the bitterness turned into sweetness - something too sweet. Then Harry realized: this was some type of artificial sweetener, which was bitter when the concentration was too high, and sweet when the concentration was right in range.

And Severus' slightly amused voice confirmed Harry's guess: "And that is the effect of saccharin," Severus glanced at Draco, and explained, "which is a food additive that Muggles use to create sweet taste without adding sugar, but it can taste bitter if the concentration is too high. Saccharin isn't really toxic, so standard spells wouldn't give you any alarm. And Mr. Potter, as for your information, some calorie-counting Muggleborn witch has recently invented a spell that can test whether some food can be considered 'healthy' per Muggle nutritional standards."

When Harry finished washing his mouth, he saw that Hermione was giving suspicious and reluctant looks at her chocolate eggplant. Then, Hermione bravely took a bite with extraordinary grace, and spat it out immediately.

When Hermione was washing her mouth and throwing diagnostic spells on herself, Severus explained with a smirk, "Nothing irregular or harmful, just our famous British cook." Then, the ex-Potion's Master's face turned stern, "However, the reason that Miss Granger didn't find out the unpleasant smell of this dish was the chocolate cake, which is now labeled 'love potion in it'. The actual irregular ingredient in that cake is named 'fairflair', a common ingredient in the magical perfume industry."

Hermione looked as if she wanted to hit her own head with a hammer, while Harry vaguely remembered reading about that potion ingredient somewhere.

Severus continued to explain. "Fairflair can create an illusion of smell that is both expected and desired by anyone. It bears resemblance to the effect of love potion in this sense, and it is used in some variations of love potion. Fairflair is not poisonous by itself, however, we have just observed how it could trick one's mind and mask any undesirable smells from the items nearby. Miss Granger, I, in particular, understand your disdain for vanity, and Witch Weekly - I have seen your face when I mentioned where to find the previous spell - yet, certain knowledge in the fashion business may prove very helpful. - And ah, Mr. Malfoy, be careful of what interesting effects you may experience when your beautification products are mixed with some other innocuous items. I would give all of you a list concerning this subject later."

As Severus was staring down at Draco, the blond boy gingerly picked up his pumpkin juice, took a small sip, carefully swallowed it down, and suddenly began to throw up.

Harry saw some small black moving dots in Draco's vomit, which might be some sort of small insects.

Severus' words weren't that reassuring this time. "Mr. Moody claimed that he doesn't know how to raise 'Gu', or the insects some Asian wizards use to control others' mind. He also claimed that he only knew how to wrap sleeping insects up with alkali, which would only dissolve upon the contact with acid in one's stomach, therefore releasing the insects; and of course, how to wake up the insects once in contact with acid. Since I have no way to verify his words, I have personally collected the non-magical insects from a random farm in France this morning, and made him taught me how to wrap them up. However, I wouldn't put it pass Mr. Moody to have spread cultivated insects all over the world, or he might have taught me some wrong methods."

Harry watched as Draco's face turning whiter by each sentence. Actually, Harry himself wouldn't put it pass Mad-Eye to have passed up on such an excellent opportunity to control a Malfoy.

-Err, Severus wouldn't really give Mad-Eye the chance to sabotage his godson, would he? However, I do have to ask Mad-Eye what he did, just in case.

"To counter this problem and some other similar problems, there are some universal solutions." Severus gave Hermione a glance, and continued. "However, those would all require the use of the Stone."

And Harry got it: we would also need a number of trolls, actually. Hmm, Severus is trying to use this opportunity to give Draco more protection. What a sneaky greasy bat.

Severus continued."There is a temporary solution that I have practised extensively recently, which is to transfigure your body into its perfect status, and then we can use the Stone to fix it."

-Oh, wait, Severus doesn't want to use the untested troll solution, just in case that has some side-effects. He is quite careful with things related to Draco. Well, on the other hand, Severus might want me to consider how to give more protection to people around me.

Harry began to contemplate whether he should give the power of trolls to Draco, Severus, Mad-Eye, Minerva, and even Mom. However, Dad probably can't survive…

Severus gave Harry and his bread a pointed look.

-Oh, well.

Harry accepted his fate, and ate a tiny bite of the bread, which turned out to be -

-Well, here is the salt we have asked for.

Chapter 40: Nurmengard, Interlude, Message to Britain

I would like to thank my beta, Kuilin.

3:42 pm, July 16th, 1993 (Kiev Time)

"Circaduplucem!" Severus wiped sweat off his forehead, panted, and reapplied the powerful disillusion charm that his rejuvenated ancestor taught him.

Salazar studied the map of Kiev in his hands, and pointed to his left, "I think the former Komitet Gosudarstvennoy Bezopasnosti of Ukraine building should be the fourth one on our left, and that is probably where we can find the wizards working for their Muggle government."

Severus nodded, and gasped, "Yes, the Muggle minister I - I used Legilimens on, thought so."

"Control yourself, Severus. Otherwise, you will be stuttering in modern English as well." The thirty-something Lord Salazar Slytherin scolded. "And your learning speed of the Slavic languages is slower than mine!"

Severus tried hard to prevent his wand hand from trembling, and followed his energetic ancestor and mentor's foot steps.

"Be quick! We haven't even figured out where they are holding the nuclear talks yet, not to mention Russian's magical discoveries." Salazar strode towards the entrance of the former KGB building.

Panting hard, Severus ran after Salazar, so that he didn't need to enlarge the circle of Circaduplucem.

What saved Severus from total magical exhaustion was the beeping sound from the double-sided mirror in his pouch. The black-haired man stopped, pulled the mirror out from his pouch, and pressed the "call-you-back-in-five-minutes" button.

"The Boy-Who-Lived?" Salazar asked.

Severus nodded.

Salazar grabbed Severus' wrist, and Apparated to their room in an upscale muggle hotel.

Severus quickly took care of his appearances, and steadied his breath.

Before Severus opened the double-sided mirror, Salazar stood in front of Severus where you couldn't see from the mirror holding in Severus' hand, getting ready to memory charm Severus in case he was pressed to utter some inconvenient truth in Parseltongue.

Severus silently thanked Salazar for not memory charming him directly, for he was so sick of being memory charmed all the time.

Severus opened the mirror, and connected to the Boy-Who-Lived.

"Professor Snape, Mr. Lucius Malfoy is being transported back to Britain to provide evidence on the crimes committed by other Death Eaters at 3 pm, London Time. It should be 5 pm in Kiev Time," Harry Potter said. "Can you come back to join us in my office then?"

Severus was silently amazed by the ex-Lord Malfoy's efficiency, and nodded. "I will be back on time."

Severus closed the mirror and sighed as he accepted his fate of being memory charmed again.

2:54 pm, July 16th, 1993 (London Time)

When Severus exited from the green flames, he received a warm welcome from Mad-Eye in the form of a number of jail-time-enabling charms. As Severus refrained from throwing deadly hexes toward Mad-Eye, and only used his Protego Vitamaxima, he snapped, "Mad-Eye, if there is ever some sort of official entitlement that proclaims that you can check on everyone, instead of others throwing all these hexes on you, please do enlighten me."

"Ha, speaking more and more like a Malfoy." Mad-Eye's magical eye jumped like crazy, and he spat, "Obtaining some important message from Grindelwald within twenty-four hours of imprisonment, am I to believe that?"

Severus refuted with a smug smile, "Mad-Eye, I know it is hard for you to absorb the harsh reality that, with Lucius' help, I have bribed out more useful information in one day than you did in one year. As the saying goes, you can't teach an old dog-"

Before Severus could finish his sentence, the Boy-Who-Lived interjected: "Professor Snape, Mr. Moody, could you please check on each other's identity, and make sure that neither of you is under any sort of mind-controlling magic? I mean, you use the same spell on each other, one spell by another, no more, no less."

Both Severus and Mad-Eye growled, and followed the Boy-Who-Lived's instructions.

Just as Mad-Eye was finally done with Severus, and claimed that there were several spells that he hadn't used on the Malfoy brat yet, the fireplace lit up again.

Madam Bones and the handcuffed Lucius stepped out of the flames.

While Mad-Eye was busy probing Lucius with all sorts of spells and magical devices, the blond man provided more things for Mad-Eye to check on: "Good afternoon, Lord Potter, Lady Granger, Severus, and Draco, my dearest son. When I visited Gellert Grindelwald this morning, he had provided me with proper wizarding garments to replace the ugly uniform provided by Nurmengard. Though I have not found any hidden message on the garments, I have worn them back here for all of you to check on. And Mr. Moody, although you might have the unfortunate instinct to just burn everything, I do need to remind you that Grindelwald is perhaps expecting me to wear something proper when I see him next time. They are all in the pouch Madam Bones brought here."

"Grindelwald's expectation, you say?" Mad-Eye jabbed a funny looking stick into Lucius's chest so hard that the blond winced, "Fantastic speed at finding a new lord."

"I can speak Parseltongue, so my loyalty is verifiable." Lucius sneered. "On the other hand, what evidence can you provide to prove your loyalty? How am I to know that you are not working for Grindelwald or anyone else?"

Observing the fire-seething Mad-Eye, Severus suddenly felt their petty squabbles were quite pathetic. If any of us here wields real power, none of this would ever happen.

With renewed determination to become all-powerful, the black-haired man rolled his eyes, and started to apply privacy and security charms around them, for he knew Mad-Eye wouldn't even let him sneeze in the general direction of the garments provided by Grindelwald before he had tested them, so for the sake of efficiency, Severus didn't try.

After the old Auror finally ran out of his tricks, and nothing abnormal was found, the real conference began.

With the memory Lucius provided, and the large Pensieve brought here by Madam Bones, they took turns and watched the entire meeting between Lucius and Grindelwald.

Severus watched as the Boy-Who-Lived and the Girl-Who-Revived put their heads into the Pensieve first, and tried to read Lucius' face. Unfortunately, the most useful expression on blond man's face was only his bitter-sweet smiles towards his son.

A while later, the Boy-Who-Lived raised his head from the Pensieve, and frowned. "Mr. Malfoy, you presented yourself as - err, I guess we can discuss that part later. More importantly, Grindelwald indeed considers Britain as his own playground; this is both good news and bad news. And now, he might think that we have means to communicate with Dumbledore, which can be good, in a while. And the last part... Err, Mr. Malfoy, did you take a look at the contents?"

"Yes, I have also provided that memory to Madam Bones." The blond man answered.

The Girl-Who-Revived was also frowning, and Severus could see a sense of unease on her face.

Severus wondered what the latter memory would be, and put his head down into the Pensieve together with his godson.

Lucius' memory started when he was escorted into Grindelwald's cell.

Severus gazed around in Grindelwald's cell, and was silently amazed by the level of privilege the former dark lord enjoyed in Nurmengard: The lords and ladies in America and the comrades in Russia do value Grindelwald's mind a lot. Hmm, I heard the American and Russian Muggles did something similar to Nazi Muggle scientists as well. I need to go back at the Muggle newspaper I read before - if my memory is correct, the Nazi scientists were not even imprisoned. Should I congratulate ourselves for having higher moral standards than the Muggles?

However, there was something else that caught Severus' eyes as well: Draco flinched a bit upon seeing his Father in handcuffs and in ugly prison uniform.

Severus sighed inwardly: The boy will get used to it. As for the pain he is suffering, well, I am hardly someone to give advice on that subject…

As Severus and Draco followed Lucius into Grindelwald's comfortable guest room, Severus patted on Draco's shoulder.

The blond boy smiled bitterly, "I just hope Father can have something similar."

Severus supposed it was highly unlikely that Lucius would become someone as powerful as Grindelwald, and Potter would hardly have the impetus to reward an ex-Death Eater with such luxuries. The black-haired man stated matter-of-factly, "Then either you or I need to be a powerful lord."

Draco avoided his eyes from Lucius as the man changed his clothes. The boy bit his lips, and nodded.

When Lucius exited the guest room, Severus and Draco followed him back to Grindelwald's living room, and observed the conversation between Grindelwald and Lucius.

As Lucius established himself as some sort of special envoy from Great Britain to Nurmengard, Severus almost congratulated Lucius on his achievement.

-Oh, this is why Lucius doesn't need to approach Grindelwald during the out-of-cell time slots, and gets there so fast. Once others consider him as such, the Americans would probably arrange things for him. And by coming back to Great Britain so fast, Lucius is confirming his role in front of every pair of interested eyes. What a sly snake!

When Grindelwald guessed that the so-called sacrificial ritual was actually an Unbreakable Vow from the little information he had, Severus' eyes almost bulged out: In the name of Atlantis, how did he managed that? Is this the level of intuition required to become a powerful lord?

Severus and Draco changed uneasy glances, as neither of them knew how to outsmart this very intelligent dark lord.

Then, Severus saw Lord Grindelwald had entered some sort of deep thinking mode. Severus felt that he had seen this sort of thing - somewhere.

-Don't tell me Grindelwald worked out a plausible ritual to explain everything from an Unbreakable Vow! This is…

Severus then had a feeling that he had recently been working on something quite similar to an Unbreakable Vow - which was…

Severus hated it when his memory became blurry, but a quick glance at Draco told him what he had worked on for more than a week: house-elves, and the rules governing them.

Severus' mind was so intent on this matter that he missed what Lucius indicated later, and how Grindelwald dismissed Lucius with a standard welcome package.

When Severus pulled his head out from the Pensieve, he heard the Potter boy said in bewilderment: "You can't swear that you know other's password, can you? I mean, how could an Unbreakable Vow possibly explain things in Grindelwald's head?"

Mad-Eye scoffed, "I've known idiots who took Unbreakable Vows, stating that they would do something they didn't possess the capability to do, and they just died from the Vow."

"Yeah, I know it wouldn't be that easy to cheat." The Boy-Who-Lived said. "Mr. Moody, you can enter the Pensieve now, and see what you can find."

While they were enjoying the absence of the roaring old Auror who wasn't sharp in powerful wizardry anyway, Severus said, "Mr. Potter, I guess Unbreakable Vows do bear resemblance to what you instructed me to work on for more than a week."

"You mean -" The Boy-Who-Lived was clearly sharp enough on this matter. "Oh, yeah."

The Girl-Who-Revived, and - to Severus's delight - his godson, also showed apprehension.

It seemed like Harry Potter wanted to say something, but he closed his mouth, and gave Granger a look.

From Potter's reactions, Severus knew there had to be something there, along the lines of imposing a rule on oneself, and that onto other magical creatures.

-Or even onto the world, such as the Interdict of Merlin. Hmm, I wonder what Merlin sacrificed when he made that Interdict.

When Severus was working on how to make an Interdict stand, an unpleasant interruption named Mad-Eye exited the Pensieve, roaring that Lucius was by no means an envoy, and began to list out reasons why this might be a plot by either Lucius or Grindelwald to end the world.

Severus rubbed his temples, "Mad-Eye, can we take a look at Grindelwald's welcome package first?"

"You're still a blood purist as the day you joint the Death Eaters, aren't you?" Mad-Eye sneered. "Admiring the Malfoys for their blood, right?"

Severus then remembered Grindelwald might have mentioned something such as "blood purity". To hide his forgetfulness, Severus rolled his eyes, "We do need to look at it, in case he left some message there."

"Err, can Hermione and I take a look at what's in there first?" The Boy-Who-Lived asked, "And then we will decide who's the proper audience."

Severus nodded, while searching Lucius' face. To Severus' slight surprise, Lucius gave him a bitter smile in response.

-Lucius doesn't seem to be too happy about the welcome package. Why is that? And since Grindelwald called it "standard welcome package", I should be able to find it elsewhere as well. If the Ministry of Magic in Ukraine runs similarly as our respected Ministry, I can probably figure something out from there.

When Potter and Granger stood up from the Pensieve, both of them held a blank face. However, the Girl-Who-Revived, who wasn't as good as hiding her emotions as the Boy-Who-Lived, had a sense of shock and disgust in her. Severus supposed, they probably saw some results from certain inhuman experiments, and they probably didn't like the conclusion much, either.

-And the boy might be up to something as well.

Severus remembered the infamous Nazi mating experiments, and guessed that it might be something of such nature.

-I wonder what the result is, that neither Lucius nor the Boy-Who-Lived likes it.

Severus asked, "Should any of us take a look at it, Mr. Potter?"

The Boy-Who-Lived's face twitched in pain as he slowly said, "Professor Snape, you alone can see it. And, would you gather information on whether some of the parts have been applied and/or improved in other places of the world? You would know what I am referring to when you see it."

Severus gave the Potter boy a strange look, nodded, entered the Pensieve, and left unpleasant sounds from Mad-Eye behind.

This time, Lucius was in his small single cell, laying down one piece of paper by another on the floor. Lucius was clearly preparing the memory to be watched by others.

-What a considerate snake!

Severus commented silently, and bent over to see the contents of the welcome package. He was instantaneously absorbed by the contents.

The title of the welcome package was Eugenics for the Benefits of Wizarding Society.

Severus had heard the word "eugenics" used alongside with the words such as "sterilization", "witch", and "freak", by none other than his own abusive Muggle father Tobias Snape in several of the many arguments he had with Eileen Snape. Severus supposed, "eugenics" might mean that people with certain inheritable traits shouldn't reproduce, or something of sorts.

The first chapter of the package discussed the magical inheritance of various types of couples.

It stated that more than 98% of children pureblood (defined as anyone with all wizarding ancestors for at least four generations) couples were magical. As for the pureblood witches who gave births to squib children, with the approval from their husbands who were probably eager to wash the stain of squib kids from themselves, or who had already suspected something, interrogators had subjected the witches to Veritaserum and Legilimens. About 50% percent of these witches or their ancestors were found guilty for crimes such as "contamination of the magical blood", and "forgery of superior blood status". Grindelwald had personally examined some of the pureblood witches and their living parents and grandparents who were cleared from all charges, and also of that of their husbands', and he had to admit that for all children born to pureblood couples with impeccable records, about 1% of them might be squibs. Severus thought, the numbers basically fitted the numbers from the pureblood families he knew.

Then, it examined the probability of wizarding children born by Muggleborn couples. With the potential infidelity problem removed, about 92% of the kids were magical, 7% were squibs, and 1% were Muggles. These numbers also made sense to Severus - Lucius and other blood purists were not complete idiots, and they actually had some numbers and examples to support their belief. And judging from here, with Severus' limited knowledge on Muggle genetics, the Boy-Who-Lived's previous idea on magical inheritance could safely go down the drainage.

Things got really interesting as pureblood-Muggle couples were examined. It showed that only 7% of the children with pureblood wizarding fathers and Muggle mothers were magical, while about 35% of the kids born to pureblood witches and Muggle fathers were magical. According to the little Muggle genetics Severus knew, this indicated that the magical inheritance was partially linked to the sex chromosome - somewhat similar to that of hemophilia. However, registration records showed that kids conceived out of wedlock in wizarding father-Muggle mother pairs had a much lower probability to be magical (~5%) than the ones born in wedlock (~15%); while in the case of witch mother-Muggle father pairs, the differences were much smaller. These statistics initially led Grindelwald's researchers to doubt whether marriage had some magical impact on magical inheritance, yet further examination showed that children conceived and born in magical environment had a much higher probability to be magical than those in Muggle environments. In the case for witch mother-Muggle father, if the witches were in strong magical environments - such as in whole-wizarding villages or in old magical houses - the whole time, the probability of giving births to magical children could go up to about 50%, yet if the witches chose to follow their Muggle partners into non-magical environments, the chances went down to about 30%. Then, the differences in numbers between males and females made a lot of senses, for the bodies of witches were obviously a much more magical environment than the mere close presence of wizards. Severus guessed, that he - and on a second thought, the Dark Lord - were among the lucky 30%.

In the case of squib couples, the statistics also showed that the environment that the children were conceived and born could have a significant effect on the probability of wizarding children. For squibs living in magical environments, the chances were about 22% - fitting the Boy-Who-Lived's data quite well, yet for those living in non-magical neighbourhoods, the probability dropped to only 8%.

As for other types of couples, such as halfblood, half-blood-squib and pureblood-squib couples, the numbers could all be explained by the combination of blood purity and environment.

From the numbers in the first chapter, it seemed that blood purists had their points. However, the second chapter showed that blood purity also came with some huge disadvantages: the decrease in fertility rates, and the increased probabilities for deformity, insanity, and homosexuality.

The number showed that in the era when an average Muggle female gave births to seven and more kids during their lifetime, squib couples had 3.1 kids, halfblood couples had 2.1 children, while the average number of children for pureblood couples was only 1.4.

As for insanity and deformity, Severus guessed he needed little data from Grindelwald to confirm that: Mad-Eye Moody was obviously paranoid, Grindelwald was cruel, the Blacks and Gaunts were well-known for their fervent pursuit of blood purity and their madness, the Potters were near-sighted, and the Crabbes and Goyles were obese. As for the Malfoys, unless you called their white blond hair a deformity, they were a lucky lot, except that they usually only had one male heir for the past one thousand year. However, Severus did hear that the Malfoys had secretly married halfblood witches, and altered the records.

Moreover, Severus did doubt that whether it was too much of a coincidence that both Dumbledore and Grindelwald were gay. The Grindelwalds were a well-known pureblood family; as for Albus, Severus didn't know much about Albus' mother, but the Dumbledores were an old wizarding family living in Godric's Hollow for hundreds of years. Also, for a long time, Severus had doubted whether Sirius Black and Peter Pettigrew were sleeping together.

From the statistics, it didn't take a genius to predict that without the constant introduction of Muggle blood into the wizarding world, wizards and witches would die out due to infertility, madness, and deformity sooner or later.

As a matter of fact, these data also explained why the percentage of wizards were always limited even in societies that considered wizarding folks as their leaders. And even for the magical creatures that could interbreed with their non-magical counterparts, the magical ones were never dominant in their numbers.

The following chapters discussed Grindelwald's solutions to the problems.

One of them was to encourage his men to marry pureblood witches, and to have casual relationships with squib and Muggle females in magical environments. The pregnant squib or Muggle women were then taken care of by some special program. Magical children born in this way were registered as half-bloods, and adopted by the many infertile magical couples; as for the squib kids born in this manner, they were handed to Grindelwald's Muggle allies' specialized camps.

Another approach employed by Grindelwald was to experiment various methods to increase the fertility rates in pureblood couples, and to increase the probability of magical births. Some methods were quite useful and harmless - Severus had recognized the recipe of a potion treating male infertility, a very similar one of which was supposedly invented by one of the American Lords in the 1950s. They also had some early experiments of cauldron babies, way earlier than the Muggles invented test tube babies. Some were much more sinister, such as a ritual that ensured the pregnant squibs and Muggles would give births of magical children. From the horrific death rates during the ritual, Severus guessed that the primary function of this ritual was to kill anyone who was not pregnant with a magical child.

Severus supposed, this was what the Boy-Who-Lived had referred to as "some of the parts have been applied and/or improved". Harry Potter probably wanted everyone to be magical in the future, yet it would be impossible unless there was some breakthrough in the magical fertility problem.

Severus sighed, and pulled his head out of the Pensieve.

As Severus was standing up, he sized the situation of the world outside the Pensieve. It seemed that Mad-Eye had kept speculating Grindelwald's evil plots.

"As I said before, nobody should ever take the damn 'standard welcome package'. Albus never did!" The old Auror roared, "I've heard about what's in it: how to kill every female who isn't pregnant with a magical child and stuff. Suits your appetite, doesn't it, Malfoy?"

Lucius rolled his eyes, "Grindelwald and his followers are all cruel - we all agree on that. Can we move on to something useful? Such as, how we should respond to Grindelwald, if we still want to continue our pretenses that we can establish some type of communications with Dumbledore?"

Mad-Eye spat, "You pretended, not 'we'!"

The Boy-Who-Lived took this chance to eye Severus, and Severus responded with a quick nod. Before Mad-Eye could issue more protests, the Potter boy said, "What Mr. Malfoy did is fine for the time being. However, we do need a long term solution, or something that could work for at least the next five years."

From the "five years" remark, Severus estimated that Harry Potter planned to become all-powerful by the age of eighteen, when regular students graduated from Hogwarts, and when Muggles were considered adults.

Severus didn't know anyone who had gained that level of power that young. The Dark Lord was an exceptional wizard who perhaps gained much ancient knowledge somewhere, yet his magic only reached that level perhaps in his late thirties or early forties. According to what Mad-Eye digged up for the story "Quirrell" told in class, soon after the Muggle martial arts school where "David Monroe" had learned much from was slaughtered in 1958, a really powerful Japanese lord named Fujimoto had chased down a relatively powerful dark lord, and almost killed him. The dark wizard only escaped with the sudden increase of luck. Considering the fact that Lord Fujimoto died a mysterious death nine years later, Severus assumed that the Dark Lord had failed in his first fight with Lord Fujimoto, and only gained the ability to assassinate the aged Japanese lord during these nine years. Although Severus didn't think he himself would be able to kill a powerful lord when he turned forty, this story did mean even Tom Riddle's power needed time to develop.

-And the Boy-Who-Lived wants to become all-powerful at the age of eighteen! I'd say Draco is more powerful than an averaged fourth year student, while Potter and Granger might be somewhere near the level of an average fifth year student. Potter is quite exceptional for his age, - but to match the power level of Albus within five years, how is that even possible?

From the rituals the Dark Lord used to make Granger hard to kill, Severus gathered that it wasn't too hard to gain physical strength and agility.

-Can this also be used to gain magic? Can you sacrifice a dragon and gain its magic? Or even, can you sacrifice powerful wizarding lords and ladies and gain the magic from that?

-Nah, even if it is possible, it would be against Potter's ethics to kill people for their magic. But dragons are probably OK to be sacrificed.

-However, we don't know if sacrificing dragons have some unwelcomed side effects. Besides, though dragons are more powerful than most ordinary folks including myself, they are not as powerful as Albus or the Dark Lord.

-If Potter wants the magical power of dragons, why five years? I suppose Mad-Eye and I can work out the details on how to sacrifice a dragon within a week or so.

As Severus was deep in his own thought, others already had several rounds of discussions on how to stall the rest of the world - plus Voldemort - from organizing an instant attack.

Lucius said, "Just as Lord Potter said, if Riddle hasn't figured out how he failed last time, he probably wouldn't be too eager to be the first serious attacker. However, what would happen if Riddle instigate other powerful wizards and witches in the world, and let them rob the Stone first, and then he will rob it from others later? With Riddle doing the persuasion, I am sure that some really powerful lords and ladies would try."

The boy who resembled Albus so much closed his eyes for a while, and then said, "Mr. Malfoy, this scenario is a logical response for - for some other dark wizards, and we do need to keep an eye on this possibility. However, for Tom Riddle, he might prefer a solo play." Harry Potter swallowed hard. "He might try to gain more power, either by learning Muggle science, or by -"

The Boy-Who-Lived glanced at Lucius, and then at Severus.

And Severus understood. Judging from Lucius' expressions, the blond man also understood.

Draco looked at his ashen faced Father, and then at his black faced Godfather. The blond boy drew in a breath, and his body tensed up.

Mad-Eye's no-longer-scarred face turned a shade whiter, and he snarled, "Damn it! I need to check on every single soul in Nurmengard!"

Lucius responded almost automatically, though his tone lost his usual sarcasm. "Be careful, some of them might be American or Russian spies. Don't cause a world war with your normal methods."

Severus pondered, and then said: "And I will look for similar signs in former Soviet states - I suppose, both in the Muggle world and the magical one. I heard there was an exodus of Muggle scientists since the Soviet Union collapsed, maybe I should look for recently disappeared distinguished Muggle scientists."

The Boy-Who-Lived nodded gravely. "Mr. Malfoy, could you tell Grindelwald that, according to the holder of Line of Merlin Unbroken's understanding of Tom Riddle, the reappeared Riddle might approach him for his biggest secret? And, err, the holder of Line of Merlin Unbroken has found the welcome package - no, the existence of the welcome package - morally unacceptable."

Then, Mad-Eye, Bones, Potter, Granger, Lucius, and Severus, who had known Albus Dumbledore from various perspectives, discussed the wording of the message, and how to make it more Albus-ish.

By six o'clock, they had agreed on the message to be delivered to Grindelwald and the rest of the world, and it was time for Lucius to be time-turned and to give testimony in the DMLE. Before the man was taken way, he looked at the Boy-Who-Lived and the Girl-Who-Revived imploringly: "Lord Potter, Lady Granger, can I spend some private time with my friend and family?"

Harry Potter's mask cracked a bit as he glanced Draco, and Hermione Granger seemed a bit uneasy.

Severus knew what Lucius was playing at - even if Severus didn't, Mad-Eye had already called it out. "You manipulative snake deserves every part of this! Don't think that you can play the pity card-"

The Boy-Who-Lived interjected, "Mr. Malfoy, you can have an hour."

After some promises in Parseltongue from both Lucius and Severus, Potter, Granger, Bones, and Mad-Eye (reluctantly, and with quite a few nudges from the Boy-Who-Lived) left the circle of privacy.

As they were waiting for Narcissa, Severus began to check what interesting spells and magical items Mad-Eye had left in this circle. The black-haired man wanted to keep himself busy, for he didn't want to consider the possibility that this might be the last time he saw Malfoy Sr. - unless he made some real breakthroughs in reviving people without their heads.

Severus knew that he was being manipulated by Lucius, but, by the time Narcissa came, he still couldn't help himself and promised: "Draco, Narcissa, don't worry too much. If anything happens, I will figure out a way to bring Lucius back, no matter what. I sspoke truth."

The three Malfoys all looked at Severus with great gratitude. Lucius walked up to Severus and gave him a hug. "My dearest Severus, my brother and my friend, you be careful yourself. If anything happens, well, you might have to wait for a while, but I shall bring you back as well. I sspoke truth"

"Godfather, me too." The younger blond also promised.

Severus knew Lucius was a bastard - Draco might be a better person, but still a little bastard. However, the black-haired man still felt the empty hole in him ever since Albus' disappearance was being filled.

-Oh, damn Malfoys!

Chapter 41: Nurmengard, Pt IV, Gellert Grindelwald

I would like to thank my beta, Kuilin.

1:24 pm, July 17th, 1993

As the heavy iron gate was closed behind the British envoy, and food disappeared from the dining table, Gellert Grindelwald pondered on the message the younger blond delivered to him.

According to Lucius, the biggest threat for Great Britain ever since Grindelwald himself, one Tom Riddle, was probably in Nurmengard, seeking Lord Grindelwald's biggest secret.

Well, Grindelwald wasn't too surprised about this news - the Americans, the Russians, and a large number of self-motivated dark wizards had been trying to find out about his real secret for the past fifty years.

-And they have tried, oh, they have tried. Brain, money, influence, promises about freedom, threats, potion, spells, rituals, torture, abduction... You name it.

What was a little bit surprise for Grindelwald was what took so long for this Tom Riddle to personally try his hands in Nurmengard.

-The new prison guard, Alexander Dimitrov, probably is Tom Riddle. The senses of darkness and danger smell right. I wonder if this new boy would try something new.

-As for the Brits sending me this message… Do they want me to kill off Tom Riddle as a ticket to the Mirror and the Stone?

Grindelwald briefly closed his eyes, and realized one thing: either they have no way to contact Albus, or they are not obeying Albus' orders.

-Albus believed in the "destiny-enemy" crap. Albus wouldn't let a dark lord kill another. They are running this show all by themselves.

Anger roared its way through Grindelwald's entire body; he wanted to tear the smug younger blond and every single Brit into pieces. However, Lord Grindelwald controlled himself soon enough.

-If Albus is really there to control everything, with his level of moral high grounds, he would never let me lay my hands on the Mirror and the Stone. Albus' absence is actually to my advantage.

-Yes, I shall study the Mirror and the Stone first, and then grant every single Brit a slow and painful death, starting with Lucius Malfoy, his precious wife, and his son.

Grindelwald summoned his communication coin, and started the long list of names that he needed to contact, starting with a signal to Lord Isaac Yodov - who was formerly Comrade Isaac Yodov: "I think I know the real reason that you lot haven't and shouldn't act the way you want."

-Damn Brits, you shall get it your way for a while, but Lord Grindelwald shall get back at you.

2:52 pm, July 17th, 1993 (Central Time)

Somewhere near the border line between the United States and Canada, a brown-haired man gave a jet black altar a last check, and then let it sink into the vast and almost endless wheatfield. Wearing a bored and disinterested expression the whole time, the man acted as if there was nothing surprising or taxing about erecting and burying such a magical wonder in a few hours in a Muggle farm in North Dakota.

Chapter 48: Space Travel Pt V, Power

I would like to thank my beta, Kuilin.

11:04 pm, July 22nd, 1993 (Almaty time)

Half an hour ago, Severus had already duplicated several spacesuits, and one charred and dented Soyuz space capsule that was said to have brought some Soviet cosmonaut back alive. Severus had also temporarily stabilized the duplicates with a duplicated Stone. However, when Severus briefly examined those strange-looking objects, he had no idea of what all the tubes connected to the spacesuits were supposed to do, nor what each part of that space capsule were used for. Severus also guessed none of the electronics in the duplicated items could be trusted. Therefore, he also needed blueprints, instruction manuals, or something of the sorts.

When Severus was seeking some Muggle in night shift who he could Legilimens near the launching pad, instinct told him of approaching danger.

White-blue shield of Protego Vitamaxima sprang out of Severus' wand without thinking, just in time to block a red bolt of light dashing towards him. Severus felt like someone had dropped some one-ton heavy weight onto his shield, and he was barely able to diverge that weight to somewhere else. In the meanwhile, Severus tried to activate the Portkey (his left sock) to his hotel room in Kiev. Unfortunately, the Portkey couldn't be activated, which meant that the enemy had banned Portkey, probably alongside with other magical travelling methods.

Severus was so familiar with this sort of situation, that it didn't require any thought process for him to throw a wordless Echolocus toward the general direction of where the red bolt had come from. Severus hoped this spell of his own invention, that utilized echo to locate the presence of disillusioned objects, could help him determine the position of the attacker.

Severus saw the green light spiraling toward his way almost at the same time as he heard "Lagann Maxima" spoken by another wizard. The powerful Breaking Drill Hex designed to break Protego Maxima failed in its attempt to crack Severus' powerful Protego Vitamaxima, yet the blow was pretty hard. Severus suspected, if he wasn't using a shield way more powerful than regular shields, he would have lost the battle already, for his opponent obviously wielded more raw magical power than he did.

Severus' Echolocus only returned a blurred image of someone in Muggle clothing wearing a pair of weird goggles when another flash of white light dashed toward Severus. The black-haired wizard dogged this time, and sent out a "Sectumsempra" toward his enemy. Severus didn't actually expect the curse that he invented to work, it was merely a cover for an inconspicuous small pebble that he was wordlessly sending toward his enemy's shield.

The ex-Head of House Slytherin was no advocate for fair play and wizarding dueling rules, so the pebble - or as the Boy-Who-Lived had called Severus' invention, a magical grenade - contained ten different hexes, several potions, and a number of interesting Muggle chemicals. When Severus made this grenade, he had figured, if his enemy was not among the top wizards, they were probably unable to handle ten hexes at once; if he or she was a top wizard besides Voldemort, the spells and potions contained in the pebble might not penetrate the shield, but the strong acid and anesthetic gas might or might not create some problems for the enemy; however, if the enemy was Voldemort, one of the spells contained in the button was actually applied by the Boy-Who-Lived, though Voldemort might have some means to block it anyway. As a matter of fact, the idea of combining multiple charms onto the same magical object wasn't anything new - people working for the Gringotts Travel Office applied a couple dozen Portkey Charms onto Portkeys everyday so that the Portkeys could carry someone from London to New York, it just took incredible skills and precision to immobilize attacking charms, let alone different attacking charms. Severus took quite some pride on being able to stabilize the Boy-Who-Lived's Turning Stunner, and to add a dozen charms of his own. Unfortunately, neither the Boy-Who-Lived nor the Girl-Who-Revived could appreciate the level of difficulty in Severus' achievement; as for people could fully understand how great this was, he didn't want to tell Mad-Eye - just in case he needed to surprise the Auror, and the old lunatic would definitely force Severus to make multiple ones for him; currently, Severus had to temporarily content himself with Lucius' well-practised admirations and praises.

Before Severus could see whether his magical grenade had worked, he found that his opponent was no proponent for fair play, either - a heavy Muggle truck was flying fast toward Severus, apparently summoned here by a wordless Accio charm. When Severus found out, it was already too late to dodge in his human form, and he didn't think his shield could handle the blow of the truck. Severus had to change into his animagus form, and flew upward as fast as he could. The large bat was barely able to escape from the main trajectory of the truck, but some metal pipes flying out of the rear of the truck still smashed into Severus' left leg. Severus thought he had heard the sound of his bones being crushed, and his entire left side became numb.

Before roaring siren deafened the echolocation system of the large bat, echoes already told Severus that his enemy had been knocked down by the device Severus sent. The large bat dropped to the smashed truck, turned into his human form, and threw several stunning and binding hexes toward the dropped figure.

Severus crawled toward his enemy, for he knew he'd better grab that guy and Apparate to somewhere before the Muggle guards got here. Then, Severus cursed his own stupidity.

"Stella, take me ... to the enemy, then bring, b-both of us to the hotel room in Kiev." Severus breathed to his bird of fire.

Two fires later, Severus was lying on the carpet of the hotel room, with his pet phoenix Stella perching by his side, cooing comforting sounds, and crying to his completely deformed left leg.

It was then that Severus had the chance to observe his unconscious enemy. That man looked sixty-something. He had grey hair and beard, a lined face, a pronounced beer belly, and he smelt like a mixture of Vodka and puke.

-My enemy is drunk?! How powerful is he when he is not drunk?

Before examining his own injury, Severus threw several other binding hexes to the man lying besides him. Severus felt that he was extremely lucky.

Just as Severus tried to sit up to see the extent of his injury, he suddenly felt another approaching danger. The lost of blood and magical exhaustion from his previous duel had drained Severus so much that his Protego Vitamaxima was only half raised when it was smashed by a red light bolt. Some dizzy moments later, the reason for his "luck" presented himself in front of Severus.

"Well done, Sseveruss." His black-haired ancestor hissed. "This guy iss indeed a good training tool for you."

-Oh, Salazar, thank you. And, you know, you could have disabled the Muggle siren, or maybe you could apply disillusion and sound-cancelling charms around your chosen dueling ground.

Severus hissed "Thank you" as he sighed inwardly. Severus figured that he need to heal himself fast, and turn back a few hours to deal with the scene.

Salazar wasn't shy about what he did for his descendant, as he absent-mindedly continued: "In this fading age of magic, it isn't that easy to find someone who is stronger than you, but not too strong for you to handle. The power level of this guard for Baikonur Cosmodrome is just right, but he was too drunk when I found him, so I had to wake him up a bit."

-Err, thank you again?

"How did this guy gain such power if he is always so drunk?" Salazar commented absentmindedly in English, while his heart was apparently somewhere else.

Severus drank down a bottle of blood-replenishing potion, pondering on what was actually bothering Salazar, and answered at the same time: "A lot of Russians become quite alcoholic - or more alcoholic - after the collapse of the Soviet Union. This might be one."

-Just as what Tobias Snape did after the mill that he had worked for ten years filed bankruptcy, and there was no need for an engineer specialized the textile industry anywhere in UK.

"Hmm." Salazar scrutinized the drunken wizard besides Severus for a while, and suddenly asked, "Did the Muggless really build the huge sspace exploring ground all by themselves? Mosstly without magic?"

Severus then realized what was probably bothering Salazar for the past two days: Salazar was so shocked by Baikonur Cosmodrome that he was desperately searching for signs of magical construction for the past two days. Plus, due to his shock, Salazar might have simply forgotten about the disillusion and sound-cancelling charms for the dueling ground.

Severus felt quite some sympathy for the medieval blood-purist, and hissed: "Yess, the Muggless did thiss themsselvess."

Salazar was silent for a long time, and only the sound of Severus' healing spells and Stella's cooing could be heard.

After a while, Salazar finally began his routine procedure after subduing his enemies, such as taking liberties with their pouches.

"What is this?" Salazar pointed a pair of green goggles, "He found you when he was wearing something like this, didn't he? Although his original pair is apparently lost somewhere, let's test if he can still see you with this when you have Circaduplucem raised."

Severus decided against annoying his mentor in distraught with minor facts such as his broken left leg, concentrated his energy, and casted: "Circaduplucem."

"Oh!" Salazar exclaimed as he held the goggles near his eyes. "I can see a blurred figure from this. Maybe this is something like your, ah, your Echolocation Charm. Very interesting."

Severus cancelled the powerful disillusion spell that was draining his energy, and gasped.

-Yeah, we need to invent something new to guard against this. By the way, if this guy knew about echolocation, why didn't he guard against it? He was too drunk or something? Or does this work differently?

Salazar duplicated the goggles, and continued his search. Holding some paperwork, Salazar commented: "Ah, this guy's name is Oleg Konstantinovich Baikov. Didn't the Smirnov guy mention something about a Baikov who was considered to have the potentials to become a Comrade, if his mentor Shakhov hadn't died? If this is that Baikov, today's wizards really have a low bar for top wizards."

"Yess, that iss the name." Severus hissed, a sense of pride rising in his heart: Merlin, I have just defeated someone who has been considered a possible future Comrade eleven years ago, which means…

"Thank you." Severus hissed to his ancestor and mentor with all his sincerity.

Salazar waved his hand, a hint of loss on his face, "Just let me continue my search."

Salazar didn't show any enjoyment towards Severus' compliments and gratitudes as he usually did, and Severus could understand why: Just as I am climbing the power ladders to become a lord like Albus, or even a lord like Salazar, Salazar is also climbing the ladders to become someone like Merlin. In the past two days, maybe he has found another power ladder, which is potentially more powerful and dangerous than the magic wielded by Merlin himself, which is Muggle technology.

Severus looked at the most powerful wizard in the world, and felt a huge wave of loss washed through him as well: The idol for all Slytherins for the past one thousand years may be able to build something like Hogwarts by himself, the most legendary wizard in history sacrificed his Life and Time to raise the Most Ancient Hall, yet none of them could construct Baikonur Cosmodrome by themselves.

After a while, Severus finally commented in English: "Maybe we can figure out how to make the Stone, or the Mirror."

Salazar bitterly smiled.

Chapter 49: Space Travel Pt VI, Prisoner's Dilemma

I would like to thank my beta, Kuilin.

9:05 pm, July 22nd, 1993 (London time)

In his headquarter office, Harry pointed to the map of the Moon, and said to Hermione: "Hermione, let's pick a place for the landing. My current idea is that we should pick a place at the back of the Moon - in case our disillusion charms go wrong, we don't want some Muggle scientists with high power telescopes on the Moon all the time to easily see it. We don't want Muggles satellites to easily see the capsule, either - can we figure out the trajectories of all the satellites orbiting the Moon? And, we may also pick a relatively flat surface, so the capsule wouldn't accidentally fall off a cliff or something. Moreover, it needs to be far away from any of the previous landing sites of Muggle lunar missions -"

Harry's words stopped as a bright light ball appeared in front of him. In the ex-Head of Slytherin's smooth voice, the light ball hissed: "I have got sseveral ssuitss and a capssule. Meet you somewhere?"

Harry hissed back: "My officce. One time passscode: 691146."

As soon as Harry finished with his spells on the fireplace, the green flames went up, and Severus limped out of the fireplace with his phoenix on his shoulder.

Noticing that Severus was hurt, alarm shot up in Harry's heart. He began to regret that he hadn't called Mad-Eye here, in case that the black-haired wizard had lost in a duel, and was now being mind-controlled by someone. Harry put care into his voice, and asked: "Professor Snape, are you alright?"

Hermione also left the sofa, and asked: "Professor Snape, do we need to call Madam Pomfrey or someone?"

Severus gave Harry and Hermione a courtesy nod, and said: "It's just physical injury, and I have already dealt with it. I will be alright in two days."

As Severus was applying privacy and security charms around them, Harry noticed that Severus' knuckles became white when he casted some of the more strenuous charms.

-This is not a good sign. The enemy Severus encountered must be quite strong. I do need Mad-Eye to check on him.

Harry hesitated, and then said: "Professor Snape, Mr. Moody and Draco are on a mission together, should I call them back?"

Severus reacted exactly the same way as Harry had expected - putting his godson together with Mad-Eye probably wouldn't lead to any positive imaginary scenes in Severus' head. The black-haired man paused, and replied: "Yes."

After Severus was done with the series of charms, he sat down in the sofa, and Stella perched besides Severus. There was nothing on Severus' face, but his strained shoulder and the slight tilt towards his right side showed that the man was still in pain.

Harry began to explain: "This morning, Draco had an idea that since we didn't know how precise phoenix travel is for super-long distance travelling, we shouldn't use Hogwarts as the landing ground - in case the space capsule appeared in the air or something. Draco proposed to use one of the places belonged to the Malfoys as landing ground. I have asked Mr. Moody to go with Draco to investigate the list of places Draco provided."

Severus' black eyes flickered, and the black-haired man commented: "A very reasonable thought indeed. Too many eyes on Hogwarts now."

Somehow, Harry sensed that Severus had known that he wasn't trusted: What did I do wrong?Where did I leak my true feelings? I should really get better with this kind of things. Well, I can probably indicate Severus that I am trying to build our trust. However, why do I have the sense that in recent days, Severus may not even care whether I trust him or not? The Malfoys, yeah, I know they are eager to please me, to show me how useful they are; but Severus, may be he just want to get things done. What happened recently that caused this change in attitude?

Harry glanced at the phoenix besides Severus, and knew the presence of Stella proved that Severus was a good man. However, in some dark corners of Harry's mind, a sound began to say: You know, maybe the cynics are right in their disregard for phoenixes - maybe they are just a show of bravery, and maybe they have some preferences for space missions, that's all.

Harry told that part of himself to shut up.

Then, the green flames lit up again. Mad-Eye and Draco stepped out from the fireplace.

Mad-Eye and Severus began their usual check on each other without Harry's command. After they were finished and both of the wizards were clear, Mad-Eye pointed to Severus' left leg and asked: "What happened?"

Severus raised one of his eyebrows, and uttered a name: "Oleg Konstantinovich Baikov."

"What?" Mad-Eye almost jumped, and began to shower another round of spells towards Severus.

Err, who is this? Harry eyed Hermione inquiringly, and it seemed that Hermione didn't know, either. Therefore, that's probably not a famous magical scholar. And according to Mad-Eye's reaction, that Baikov guy seemed like a powerful dark wizard.

Severus raised his Protego Vitamaxima, and proudly announced: "I defeated him."

Mad-Eye's reaction was to throw the pebble that Harry gave him toward Severus, and the black-haired man quickly deflected the pebble toward the window.

Before the window was shattered by the combination of ten simultaneous spells, corrosive potions, and strong acid, Severus jumped out of the couch, enlarged his shield to protect everyone from the blast, and yelled: "Mad-Eye, are you mad? I am not You-Know-Who! I am just three steps from Potter and Granger. Ask what they feel!"

Harry had to confirm Severus on this: "Mr. Moody, I don't feel the sense of DOOM."

Although Severus was currently protecting him, Harry could tell that the black-haired man wasn't too happy about the fact that his own creation was used against him, nor the apparent fact that Harry had handed Mad-Eye at least one of the ten magical grenades that Severus gave Harry - Harry had let Mad-Eye check the grenades without telling Severus, but now it seemed that Harry should have played the honest card and consulted Severus first.

-Well, I guess now it doesn't take an ex-Head of Slytherin to figure out that I don't trust him.

-Hopefully, Severus could take some pride in the fact that Mad-Eye considered the magical grenade the most effective weapon against You-Know-Who.

-How should I appease Severus with this? Or worse, does him still need it?

Mad-Eye pointed his wand toward Severus: "Lad, you gained too much power, too quickly. You'd better have a very good explanation for this. Potter, Granger, what are you thinking? Move away from him! There are other dark wizards besides Voldie!"

Harry chose not to move a single step, for if the black-haired wizard in front of them wanted to hurt him or Hermione, he already had the chance; even if the possible hand behind Severus had some evil plots, doing it right in front of Mad-Eye probably wasn't a good idea. Therefore, Harry stayed asked: "Who is this Baikov? Why is defeating him such a big deal?"

"Someone who is considered to be able to join the ranks of the Comrades." Mad-Eye spat, both eyes firmly on Severus, "Stronger than either me or the Snape lad I know."

Harry couldn't see Severus' expression, but he imagined that the black-haired man had rolled his eyes as he answered sarcastically, "You need to update your information, Mad-Eye. That was eleven years ago, before his mentor Shakhov died. After Baikov failed in some power scrambles in Moscow, he was demoted to Kazakhstan, and developed a preference for Vodka ever since. And after the collapse of the Soviet Union, his problems grew worse. So yes, the Baikov I defeated was a wasted drunk. He broke my leg, but I stunned him with the pebble that I invented - and by the way, the device which you just shamelessly used on me." Severus turned to Harry with a blank face, "I sspoke truth."

-Oh, this is such a great example of my failed leadership! And Severus has defeated a drunken Comrade-to-be, which means that Severus is more powerful and/or resourceful than Mad-Eye thought. Maybe Severus has seen the potential of he himself becoming an all powerful lord, so he is no longer as eager to please me as when he just came back.

-Hmm, the the level of fine control of magic Severus exhibited in combining all the charms, potions and chemicals into a small pebble might be quite remarkable. I have thought since Hermione could learn to overlay seven Portkey Charms to make a Portkey from Moscow to London without too much practise, and wizards working for the Goblins make Portkeys from New Zealand to the Great Britain all the time, overlaying charms wasn't that difficult. Yeah, Mad-Eye didn't use a magical grenade that he himself made, that meant he couldn't make one himself. Otherwise, Mad-Eye would never use something that Severus made against Severus. Oh, and Mad-Eye didn't tell me that he couldn't make good magical grenades after I showed them to him, which meant that he was either overestimating his own abilities, or he was refusing to admit defeat.

-How delightful!

Harry sighed inwardly, and made a note to himself that needed to talk to Severus and Mad-Eye separately afterwards. He confirmed to everyone that Severus had spoken truth, and asked both Severus and Mad-Eye to sit down and be civil to each other.

Draco carefully sat by Severus, and asked in a low voice: "How are you, Godfather?"

Severus' alert black eyes never left Mad-Eye, but his voice took on a hint of warmth as he answered: "Don't worry, it's just physical injury, caused by a stray iron pipe from the back of a truck Baikov tried to throw at me. Easy to heal."

Harry asked: "How was your mission, Professor Snape?"

Severus took out a green pouch from his black pouch, and then from the green pouch, he retrieved three sets of spacesuits, and a charred and dented space capsule that was approximately the size of an adult acromantula.

Harry still had some difficulty in accepting the multiple folding of space - not to mention how the large space capsule was fitted into the small opening of the pouch, yet other wizards seemed to have taken all this for granted. Harry knew this wasn't the best time to inquire about pouch magic, so he put on a happy face, and exclaimed: "Professor Snape, thank you! We can begin to work on them very soon."

Harry guessed that he didn't quite make the exclamation in the right tone to appease Severus, but the black-haired perfect Occlumens showed nothing on his face.

-Damn! I have only been leading people who are eager to serve me, who would ignore my blunders. Severus ... is a new challenge. What the heck happened between the guilty man in front of me a month ago, and this proud Lord-wannabe, or even Lord-to-be? The most significant change that I know is that he has a godson now. Does having Draco in his life give him a purpose or something? But it doesn't feel quite right. Unfortunately, Draco wouldn't be of much help in figuring this out. As for Mad-Eye, nah, he would only give answers such as Severus has been serving Grindelwald and/or Voldemort and/or some other dark wizards recently.

Severus nodded, and said: "Mr. Potter, and Miss Granger, maybe you two have some advantages in figuring out what everything on them does, so that we can know what to do to construct a magical equivalent. I encountered Baikov before I could get blueprints or manuals for these items. I suppose, I can go back to Kazakhstan after my leg is healed."

Harry had no other choice than to appear to be a caring leader: "Professor Snape, please take enough time to rest, and maybe have Madam Pomphrey to check on you."

Severus nodded again as he said: "Mr. Potter, I have a suggestion on our animal test. I think we should put a snake and a note with Interdicted magic written in Parseltongue on it, just to see if going to the Moon is enough to bypass the Interdict of Merlin. I can use my healing time to select a snake, and teach it how to read."

-Err, what?

"Parseltongue has a written form?" Harry asked in surprise. "Can you lie when you write things down in Parseltongue?"

"Yes, and no, for your questions." Severus seemed to be a little amused by Harry's ignorance, "Generally speaking, Parseltongue resembles Old English. For example, the spelling of words isn't really fixed, and for the most part, you just need to spell the words out from the letter-to-sound correspondence."

"Can someone who can't speak Parseltongue learn to read and write in it?" Harry asked.

Apparently, this had never occurred to Severus, for the man hesitated, and answered: "I don't know."

-This is HUGE! The pronunciation of Parseltongue is way too hard for a normal person to grasp, but learning some snake-ish letters may not be that difficult. If there is some method to force everyone to speak truth, we may even figure out a way to partially solve the prisoner's dilemma!

Just as Harry got all excited about the idea, in a small corner of his mind, Hufflepuff spoke: Have you forgotten something? Severus has just proposed to send a sapient being who is made to follow orders given by Parselmouths to space, not to mention that sapient being is clever enough to learn to read.

Slytherin sneered: Or what? Sending Severus up to the Moon first? He is clearly sapient, clever enough to read and write, and creative enough to invent magical devices, charms and potions.

Harry decided to consult Hermione in private about the moral dilemma, but he could decide on another matter now: "Professor Snape, could you teach everyone here how to read and write in Parseltongue? Err, maybe you and Mr. Moody can learn to trust each other after you can both write in Parseltongue."

Severus seemed to want to roll his eyes or sneer, but he stopped himself, and said: "Of course."

OK, Step One is done. Harry took in a breath, and turned to Mad-Eye: "Mr. Moody, how did the investigation of the Malfoy farms go?"

Chapter 51: Space Travel Pt VIII, Bionics

I would like to thank Kuilin for editing this chapter.

8:25 am, July 25th, 1993 (Kiev time)

Severus skimmed through the third page of Magical Pravda delivered to his hotel room in Kiev, and found that Baikov was merely fined twenty galleons by the Kazakhstan Ministry of Magic for the incident where he reportedly got too drunk and thought flying trucks would be fun. Of course, Magical Pravda, which was published in Moscow, reported this in a mocking way - probably to show its readers what a chaos the other former Soviet states were in, so that its readers would feel better about their own lives, which wasn't great, either. It seemed that after Soviet Union collapsed, the magical society in Kazakhstan finally reversed back to how things should be run in the magical society: the most powerful wizard in the nation could safely disregard rules set by regular people as long as they pleased, instead of obeying the ridiculous rules set by Shakhov or the laws accepted by Dumbledore, where bureaucrats like Smirnov could intimidate the students of Comrades. Therefore, Baikov, who was currently the most powerful wizard in Kazakhstan, and who could be quite unreasonable after several bottles of Vodka, escaped the incident on July 22nd unscathed.

Although Severus agreed that powerful witches and wizards should have privileges, and he didn't want the innocent man to be in too much trouble, this quick turn of events certainly didn't quite work in Severus' way. Severus got mentally prepared to duel Baikov or someone like Baikov again, and planned his journey accordingly.

Severus briefly praised himself for the many benefits that the raid of the British Library provided. For example, before the raid, none of the people on their side knew that NPP Zvezda was the primary spacesuit manufacturer in former Soviet Union. And although the Boy-Who-Lived had some vague memory of the name "RSC Energia", his memory didn't quite put that name together with the Soyuz spaceships, nor did he knew where the company was. Now with the results from the book raid, Severus had a clear idea about where to go, and what to get from these places. However, a trip to Baikonur Cosmodrome was still necessary, for they needed more detailed information on space launches and retrievals. Moreover, three days ago, due to Severus' injury and fatigue, and the fact that he was running out of time on his Time-Turner, Severus' search and investigation of Baikov wasn't as thorough as he hoped - he didn't even get any notes with things that he couldn't understand.

After going over the list of things that he would need to get from NPP Zvezda, Severus applied the usual sequence of concealing charms, plus one extra - according to the Boy-Who-Lived and his dad, since the color saw through the green goggles that Baikov wore exhibit more intense colors for the fireplace than a human being, the goggles were some sort of heat detection - something called "infrared". Thanks to the creativity of generations of criminals, Mad-Eye already knew a charm that could mask the true temperature of things, and it could work against the green goggles. Therefore, Severus added a "Temperacelus" charm to his usual sequence. This matter also served as a warning to Severus, that he wasn't the only wizard who could think of other detection methods besides the regular sense of human being. Professor Verres-Evans had said that certain kinds of snakes had infrared detectors as well. Severus wondered if the sneaky Blue Krait had the thing called "pit organs", and conveniently hid the fact from everyone. Well, considering the fact that Severus hadn't told Lucius about his echolocation system - though the blond bastard probably had already figured it out - Severus could only blame his own stupidity and ignorance of Muggle biology.

Severus sighed inwardly, and applied the same sequence of charms on Stella. "Stella, let's go to the southeast side of Moscow, and get both of us some material for spacesuits."

Stella cawed, and a flame later, Severus began to look for proper Muggles to Legilimens for the exact location of the spacesuit production place in NPP Zvezda. After two days in Baikonur Cosmodrome, Severus already got better with identifying proper Muggles and navigating through the ugly and clunky Russian buildings. Moreover, luckily for Severus, although certain signs showed that Zvezda had once been guarded by wizards like Baikov, it was no longer the case now. A few hours later, Severus got duplicates of multiple spacesuits that looked different from the ones that he already had, plus enough lithium oxide, active charcoal, compressed oxygen and air tanks, and other consumable supplies he directly stealed - Severus didn't want to trust his life on transfigured Muggle chemicals. Judging from the level of theft that became so common these days in this country, Severus supposed the Muggle wouldn't even be surprised. However, just to be safe, Severus still fabricated a scene where some Muggle manager took the materials, and inserted the memory into the mind of two Muggle storehouse keepers, and left them some rubles as tips.

The trip to RSC Energia went quite smoothly as well, where the biggest challenge had been how to find the things he needed.

By 7:30 pm Moscow time, which was 4:30 pm Almaty time, it was time for Baikonur Cosmodrome again. Severus licked his lips, and said to Stella: "Stella, let's go to somewhere outside the apartment building of Baikov's home."

This time, Severus decided that he would subdue Baikov and search his apartment first, instead of worrying where that wizard would be all the time while he was in Baikonur Cosmodrome - Severus really wanted to know the secrets of Shakhov's Hammer among other Interdicted magic, and there was no better time to grab them than before his trip to the Moon.

Severus landed among several yellow apartment buildings. By this point, Severus already got used to the strange custom the Russian Muggles adopted - for some reason, all the apartment buildings across the former USSR looked almost identical to each other, and a wizard could easily mistake an apartment complex in Kiev for one in Almaty. Severus needed check the plates on the buildings and his echolocation charm to know which one was the building that he was looking for. To Severus' slight surprise, his echolocation charm pointed out at least five apartments that had magically concealed something. Severus reasoned that there could be other magical guards who lived around here. Severus could see that the magic on three of these apartments showed signs of wearing out, which might mean that owners were no longer maintaining them. Severus decided that he need to check these places as well, just in case it was some sort of cover-up on Baikov's side.

Severus focused his echolocation charm on the apartment that was three windows away from Baikov's supposed home, where the window was opened a slit, and -

A stout figure with a bottle in one hand and a wand in another was peeking out from the window.

It seemed that Baikov, who was once considered a Comrade-to-be, wasn't a completely wasted idiot after all. Probably, he had developed some suspicion on the events three days ago. And Baikov probably had occupied vacant apartments, and he had magically altered the inner structure of the part that he took as residence.

Severus knew that challenging a prepared wizard who was more powerful than yourself at his own place was an extremely bad idea. Therefore, he needed to cheat.

Severus thought for a while, and then turned towards the nearest liquor store. Severus estimated, if there were a long queue of people lining up in the front door of the liquor store, Baikov should be able to notice the commotion, and might decide to add something to his Vodka storage. If this failed, Severus wouldn't lose much except some cheap liquor, which, for some reason, worked better than money in equal amounts in the former USSR.

A few memory charms later, the two salesman there both thought that they had gotten quite some Vodka cheaply from black market, and they needed to sell the hard liquor after hours behind their manager's back. Therefore, after the manager left after the store was closed, the two salesman returned, and secretly called their friends. Within ten minutes, people began to rush toward the liquor store, and all left with quite some Vodka that Severus secretly put in the storage . And as good Russians did, a lot of people began to line up upon seeing that there were people in front of a store, without even asking what the line was for. And after they knew it was cheap Vodka, many rushed to get more cash.

As Severus had expected, Baikov noticed the commotion. And Severus was sure, with some simple charms, Baikov could hear what the long line was for.

Maybe years of alcohol consumption had compromised Baikov's judgement, maybe Shakhov had taught his student too well, Baikov didn't directly Apparate to the storage room of liquor store, and took liberties from there. Instead, the most powerful wizard in Kazakhstan left his home on foot to join the line for cheap Vodka.

The second that Baikov stepped near Severus' magical trap at the entrance of the apartment building, Severus simultaneously trigger five magical pebbles, three fully loaded with Breaking Drill Hexes, stunners, powerful sleeping hexes, and anesthesia gases, and the other two loaded with light, sound and shock-wave cancelling charms.

The most powerful wizard in Kazakhstan was a lot more alert and powerful when he was not fully drunk, but clearly, he wasn't thirty times more powerful than Severus. Baikov's shield and magical protective items all winked out before all the spells on the three attacking pebbles were released. Needless to say, Severus bounded Baikov with more ways before he cleaned the scene.

"Stella, let's go to the hotel room in Kiev." Severus grabbed Baikov, and said.

A flame later, Severus began his thorough search on Baikov and his pouch. Just as Severus was half way through with Baikov's pouch, Stella suddenly cawed. Severus' wand moved faster than his mind, it was after Severus jabbed his wand on the throat of the grey-haired man on the floor that Severus realized Baikov's fingers twitched.

"Don't move!" Severus demanded with the best American accent he could manage. Thanks to Shakhov Vocational School, Baikov should be able to understand English.

Baikov slowly opened his eyes, and saw Severus as he took off the disillusionment.

Of course, Severus still have some magical and non-magical concealments on, he just showed his face to have a smoother conversation.

"It was you, I know it!" The man on the floor groaned with a heavy Russian accent.

"You know what I want." Severus calmly said, just in case he could cheat some extra information out from Baikov.

"You're here after the Muggle space technology, aren't you? Where are you from? France? Japan? China? India?" Baikov asked instead.

Severus felt a bit ashamed of his Muggle countrymen that they weren't even considered potential opponents in the space race, and Severus supposed, Baikov didn't mention the Americans because the Americans already got what they wanted. Plus, Baikov might have been trained to give true but elusive information to interrogators by the KGB, which added problems to this conversation.

"It doesn't matter where I am from. I can be quite generous." Severus decided to directly ask, "What progresses have Russians made with magic and space technology?"

A flash of pain passed through Baikov's blue eyes as he answered: "Ah, not much. You know, magic doesn't work well with electronics."

"What were the successes and failures? What happened when you tried to send wizards up to the space?" Severus knew Baikov wasn't giving any real information. He asked more specifically.

"Wizards blow up rockets, I assume you already know?" Baikov smiled sardonically. "Or maybe I shouldn't tell you, so there is a chance that one of yours would become a gigantic fire."

Severus briefly wondered if he should try torture, but the disillusioned Stella cried angrily toward him.

Severus sighed inwardly: Merlin, should I give up all my evil thoughts from now on?

Baikov heard phoenix's cry, and exclaimed: "A phoenix?! You have a phoenix? You are from the Great Britain!"

Severus almost groaned. Well, given the fact that the only known domesticated phoenix was Fawkes, it wasn't a hard guess - in recent history, there had been one owned by a New Zealand wizard when he fought against Grindelwald, but the owner passed away under some mysterious conditions in the 1950s; the phoenix owned by a brave and powerful Russian sorceress, but the witch was killed by none other than Grindelwald himself; and Severus heard a Gryffindor got a phoenix shortly after Severus graduated Hogwarts, but that student failed to save anyone he wanted to save, and was killed in the first mission.

"How did you know that I didn't get a new one?" Severus replied.

Baikov replied: "Nah, too unlikely. - Wait, you want to, you get this phoenix to, to - " The most powerful wizard in Kazakhstan stuttered.

-Shit! Should I erase his memory, and do this again?

Baikov was relieved, and excited: "Oh, you have a phoenix! You can't be an evil guy."

Severus was quite annoyed when someone pointed out that he couldn't torture or kill innocent people anymore, unless he could honestly explain to Stella that by not doing so might endanger an entire planet - which was clearly not the case here. Severus gritted his teeth, and considered erasing Baikov's memory, and conduct this conversation all over again.

Baikov continued: "How did you get this phoenix? We wanted to try that, phoenix, but Dumbledore was the only one who owned it!"

"Dumbledore didn't agree to try this idea?" Severus was more surprised about the implication that Dumbledore didn't agree than the fact that someone had wanted to try.

"Oh, we didn't ask. I guess the Americans weren't exactly friends with Dumbledore, either." Baikov was still quite excited.

Severus supposed, he shouldn't be too surprised about the fact that the world was loaded with politically shrewd idiots, and this made him feel a little bit better for his upcoming mission, since nobody had failed with a phoenix-powered space mission yet.

Baikov continued: "You know, I have always been thinking, when I want to end - OK, by the end of my life, I would get into a space capsule, grab it, and get it to side-along Apparitions with me multiple times, and see where I can get to until -"

Severus knew the distance one could Apparate had an limit. For someone like Severus himself, the limit for one Apparition was approximately eight hundred miles; and Severus estimated, if he were to grab something as heavy as a space capsule to side-along Apparate with him, the distance would be limited to somewhere around forty miles, not to mention that he needed to keep the relative position of himself and the space capsule all the time. Severus did a quick estimate, and found that he himself would probably lost the grasp on the relative position, and be killed within four or five Apparitions, which wasn't even enough distance for bypassing the half-botched Interdict on Electronics, not to mention the Interdict of Merlin. Even if Baikov was twenty times stronger than Severus, Severus still estimated that Baikov would be killed before he reached the so-called "geostationary orbit". Severus hoped he had spelt the name of the orbit right - anyway, according to the Boy-Who-Lived, that's where a lot of satellites stayed. However, from the way Baikov spoke about it, Severus guessed that had been Baikov's suicide plan for quite a while - maybe because of the collapse of the Soviet Union, or maybe because of his failure in the power games in Moscow, Baikov wanted to pursue something more meaningful than the petty mundane matters on Earth. However, it seemed Baikov had given up on an immediate suicide plan, probably thanks to the news about the Stone. And this meant -

Severus smiled to himself, and asked: "What preparations have you made for your plan?"

Baikov gazed Severus for quite a while, then answered: "If you swear you are going to the space, and tell me the result if you succeed, I will tell you."

Severus frowned: "You want an Unbreakable Vow? Are you trying to have a third person here as an escape plan?"

Baikov answered: "No! You see the golden Vodka bottle that you've casually thrown over there? It is an one-time Hammer - you know the Hammer, right? I can tell you how to make an one-time Hammer if you come back alive."

Severus thought of it for a while, and then answered: "I have to block your memory for a while, and you can't reveal it to anyone or anything in any way or form at anytime under any circumstances. And I have other requests as well."

In another room of the same Muggle hotel, Salazar let out a sigh: In the name of Atlantis, one day, I shall tell Godric how much work I have done to Baikov and Severus to make them this gullible. Otherwise, I can hardly figure out a way to let Severus explain the source of my many uninterpretable notes. And this would certainly undermine Severus' relationship with my crazy descendant.

-By the way, the Boy-Who-Lived's Muggle stepfather said that some snakes have pit organs, but I don't have it. Hmm, I heard Merlin could adapt many animagus forms, wonder if I can do something about my animagus form, or if I can change into another type of snake.

-And there is something else that I need to figure out. It seems that the mudblood unicorn girl can learn to read written Parseltongue. How can this be possible? Is one of the two squib servants my descendant? This is such a dreadful thought.

Note: Kraits don't have pit organs, so Lucius was wrongfully blamed here - his reputation didn't do him a lot of good here.

Chapter 52: Space Travel Pt IX, PC or NPC?

I would like to thank Kuilin for betaing this chapter.

7:34 am, July 26th, 1993

In his headquarter office, Harry subconsciously tossed the scrambled eggs around in his plate, and sighed: "So, that's about all what Severus has told me on his dealings with Baikov - in Parseltongue. Hermione, I am not so sure what to make of the whole matter."

Hermione's face was also grim. She said: "Harry, I need a while to think about it."

Harry nodded, and said: "Take your time."

Judging from his interactions with Baikov, Severus Snape is acting all by himself now. Slytherin coldly said. We shouldn't allow this kind of behavior. The Malfoys are leverages that we can use against him.

Hufflepuff quietly reminded him: Severus has never sworn his loyalty to us, remember? And we all agree that there is nothing wrong with people having their own judgement. Moreover, although this might not mean the same to us as Hermione's life being in danger, we do have to realize that Severus' life is at risk - he surely cherishes his own life, and Lucius and Draco care about his life to a certain degree. Severus' judgement called him to maximize his chances of staying alive.

That's exactly the problem. I agree people can have their own judgement, as long as they don't act on it. A corner that was much darker than Slytherin seethed through his teeth. We need to invent something like the Mark of Light.

Gryffindor roared in righteous fury, Hufflepuff gasped in absolute horror, and even Slytherin frowned.

Harry told his dark side to shut up.

Ravenclaw spoke up: Hey, aren't we even curious about what Severus got from Baikov? From my point of view, we can't call Severus' agreement with Baikov a bad one. Let's face it, Baikov was a student of the most powerful wizard in Russian - a lot of people have ranked Shakhov right below Dumbledore and Grindelwald. Severus managed to get quite a stack of notes from Baikov on Interdicted magic, and he did this without even promising Baikov that he would tell him about any of the magic he gained from the notes afterwards. This was a miracle, no less. If we were given the chance, we would definitely do the same as Severus did.

-Err…

Even Dark Harry had to admit that Severus had somehow pulled out a miracle - without consulting Harry. It is well-known that it was very hard to get information from powerful wizards who were also perfect Occlumens. The world's top wizards had tried to extract information from Grindelwald for almost fifty years now - Lucius had said he guessed some had secretly tried torture, but obviously that nothing had broken someone like Grindelwald. Moreover, Baikov knew how to make an one-time Hammer, therefore he probably already sealed himself against unwanted release of information, just like "Nicolas Flamel" did.

Slytherin pondered: Baikov has worked in the Cosmodrome for eleven years, he had done some serious preparations for his suicidal space mission for several months before the news about the Stone stopped his suicidal thoughts, and he continued that work now and then as a hobby after a few bottles of Vodka. Therefore, if we want to maximize the probability of success of this mission, which is possibly vital for winning this war, then retrieving information from Baikov is a good thing to do. And with Baikov's stolen and magically modified Soyuz return capsule and his semi-finished spacesuit, this could have saved us months of time, and hence this is a vital opportunity. However, I have a feeling that Severus is increasingly seeing himself as an ally to us, not as a subordinate. We need to quench this idea, and have a tighter leash on Severus - this is for Severus' own good. That man has troubles with seeing dangers even when it is right in front of him. He himself confessed on that shortcoming a month ago.

Hufflepuff quietly suggested: Hey, maybe it is time for us to learn how to have an ally...

And Hufflepuff's arguments were cut off by Hermione: "Harry, I think I would agree with you on certain points that you might argue, such as security implications. There are several things that I would like to point out. First, although I still think Severus has some problems telling the differences between right and wrong, Stella would cry at him if he were wrong, so this decision can't be evil. Second, with Stella on Severus' side to help with character judgment, Baikov probably isn't a bad person. However, as a matter of fact, I am more concerned for you than the whole matter - you weren't that excited about Baikov's desire to explore space, or that you might have finally met someone who shares your dream."

-Ahh…

Harry didn't quite know what to say. He had always thought that exploring other galaxies would be the next great step for sapient beings on Earth, and he had often complained about why so many intelligent people just busied themselves with mundane daily matters, instead of something that could save the entire race. However, when another clever wizard turned out to have similar ideas, Harry's own mind also focused more on the pity strugglings among human beings.

-Have I fallen into the same trap that has prevented humans from attaining true greatness?

Hermione continued: "Harry, I think I see what the problem is. You see most people you don't know as NPCs. You see me as a PC, so you are really excited when I share values with you; Severus is probably somewhere between a PC and a NPC in your mind, so you are also quite happy when it turned out that he wanted to revive someone, too. However, when someone you don't know - such as Baikov - also shares some rare ideas with you, it's more or less like a great plot in a science fiction book."

-Err…

Hufflepuff said: Hermione is right. We do see most people as NPCs. And the previous horrible idea about the Light Mark is a perfect example of this train of thought. By imposing the Light Mark, we reduce our followers into NPCs in a RPG game. And that's exactly what Voldemort has done by the Dark Mark - reducing people to NPCs. And see what came out of that - Severus' betrayal might or might not fit into the Prophecy that led to Voldemort's first failure; Voldemort ended up floating in the space for ten years because he didn't tell Bellatrix where to find even one of his many horcruxes; and Voldemort had no idea that two of his most powerful servants were Parselmouths...

Gryffindor also raised a point: You know who had actually imposed a "Light Mark" to many people? Comrade Mikhail Andreyevich Shakhov. And see how that ended up for the cause he fought for - his "NPCs" overthrew Soviet Union after he died, just to get rid of the "Light Mark". Remember, Shakhov's cause was only Communism and the Soviet Union. Do you want to imagine what our subordinates would try to get rid of their "Light Mark"?

Even Slytherin agreed: Now even I feel lucky that we refused Professor Quirrell's suggestion about the Light Mark the moment he raised it.

Cold sweat ran down Harry's spine even as he felt lucky.

"... Treating people as PCs is also benefiting us in other ways. Remember our first mock battle? Back then, Sunshine won the battle by combining the wits of other people. Like you told me, when Severus and Lucius had - or they thought they had - good ideas, they told you about the ideas. I bet they never did that with You-Know-Who. Harry, not only people who are near us are PCs -" Hermione paused in mid-sentence, and carefully asked, "What happened, Harry?"

"Err, I wholeheartedly agree with you, that people are not NPCs. And I shall never impose any Light Mark -" Harry found that he had let his mind slip, but he decided to finish his sentence anyway, so that Hermione would know another circumstance where she had to stop him or anyone else who might try the same, "- onto anyone."

"You, what?" Hermione asked in disbelief.

Harry then explained to Hermione how Dark Harry had come up with the idea, and how the result of the Cold War had taught him better.

Hermione stared at Harry in wide eyes. After quite a while, she said with a bit of stutter: "O-OK, Harry, I understand. And, of course, I would try my best to stop anyone who would try this approach."

Harry gravely nodded.

Chapter 55: Space Travel Pt XII, Abilities of Phoenixes

6:52 pm, July 27th, 1993

Harry stared at the data they collected today for phoenix energy and food consumption, with Dad laughing hard and Hermione giggling in the background.

Originally, Harry had estimated phoenixes would consume similar amount of oxygen and food as non-magical birds of the same size. However, Stella proved that assumption wrong once and again.

First, Stella was asked to sleep in the dormant status in the transparent measurement box, which Dad provided the design, Severus transfigured into reality, and fixed by the Stone. The oxygen she consumed and carbon dioxide she produced was only approximately 1/150 of a sleeping non-magical turkey, measured with the same set of device. This meant phoenixes were really efficient in energy conservation, which wasn't that surprising according to the standards of magic, but that was enough to make Professor Michael Verres-Evans' eyeballs drop - he couldn't understand how a bird with slightly higher body temperature than a human being could use so little energy.

The second experiment was to measure the metabolism rate of Stella when she was awake and walked around in the measurement box. This time, the oxygen consumption and carbon dioxide production was about one tenth of that of a turkey. Considering the fact that Stella was going on a trip to the Moon, this was a good news.

Then, Harry asked Severus what kind of food phoenixes ate. Severus answered that he had seen Fawkes eating Dumbledore's sweets, while Stella preferred cuttlefish. Harry wanted to ask whether Severus liked cuttlefish, and whether Severus had conveniently omitted certain food items that were attractive to bats, but he decided to ask how much food Stella ate per day instead. To this question, Severus slightly frowned, and answered: "Stella seems to have an almost bottomless stomach. I have once fed her about ten kilograms of cuttlefish, she not only ate all the meat, but also did it without any apparent increase in her weight. And from the looks, she could eat a lot more. However, Stella can also go without eating anything for a whole day."

Harry knew Aguamenti produced water without the disappearance of water from any known lake, and there was a charm named "Arresto Momentum", so the Conservation of Mass, Energy and Momentum Laws of Muggle physics didn't really apply while magic was around. However, this was still somewhat hard for Harry to accept without seeing it with his own eyes.

Harry took out a mechanical balance from his pouch, and asked Stella to stand on it. The balance said 10.4 kilograms. Harry asked a house-elf to get one pound of cuttlefish, and let Severus fed Stella. As the amount of meat on Severus' hand diminished, Harry watched the number on the balance grew slowly from 10.4 to 10.9 kilograms, and suddenly, with a few flaps of wings, the number dropped to 10.5 pounds.

Professor Michael Verres-Evans' eyeballs dropped again, and so were Harry's.

-Stella converted most of the food she just ate into carbon dioxide and water with a few flaps of wings?

That was the only reasonable Harry could come up with, and he had to test this. Therefore, Stella and ten pounds of cuttlefish were put into the transparent measurement box, this time with a larger mechanical balance below the whole system. Stella seemed to enjoy this part of the experiment a lot, for she happily ate the cuttlefish, with occasional flaps of wings. To Harry's slight relief, the weight of the entire system stayed constant, which meant that the Conservation of Mass still applied here. Harry knew this didn't mean much in face of the arbitrary acceptance of Muggle physics by magic, but it was good to know some part of the magical world still ran in similar laws as in the Muggle one.

Just at this moment, Hermione yelled urgently: "Stella, are you comfortable?"

Stella raised her head, curiously cawed, and turned back her food.

Everyone looked at Hermione curiously, and the Girl-Who-Revived explained: "This device was designed to measure slow oxygen consumption and carbon dioxide production, so it provided oxygen from the oxygen tank slowly. If my estimation is right, each time Stella flaps wings, the oxygen level in the box should drop to around 1% to 4%, and this could lead to suffocation in seconds for non-magical animals."

And apparently, Stella didn't care about how the stupid respiratory system of non-magical animals worked. She just pecked the cuttlefish, and occasionally flapped her wings, consuming the majority of oxygen in the container.

Harry knew what Stella was doing was not that impressive by the standards of magic - for whatever reason, his pouch could ate heavy books without any increase of weight on a mechanical balance - but this was still amazing.

-And in the name of Atlantis, how do phoenixes store energy?

Professor Michael Verres-Evans was also admiring the golden-red firebird, and said in a mesmerized voice: "Oh my God, Stella is designed for space travel, isn't she?"

Before Harry knew about magic, he had been against the idea that the appearance of any natural animal was "designed" by some higher power. However, the two years in the magical world already taught him better. Wizards had been breeding magical animals according to their arbitrary designs for thousands of years. For example, after reading the Auror interrogation reports on Hagrid, Harry had absolutely no idea how the half-giant cross-bred fire crabs, which were a kind of arthropods with gems on their shells (if Muggle taxonomy meant anything here), with manticores, which were sapient lion-like mammals with human-level intelligence. Harry didn't really want to ponder on the ethic questions on how Hagrid made a proud English-speaking creature to mate with a crab, or whether blast-ended skrewts were sapient.

Therefore, Harry decided to test the bold hypothesis that Dad proposed. After several hours of testing, it seemed that Dad was right: Stella could withstand heat up to 150 degrees Celsius; and she could stay in a container submerged in liquid nitrogen for at least 15 mins, and the inside temperature of the container was around -150 degrees Celsius with firebird's slight heating. Stella could also live with low oxygen level and low vacuum, for 1 Torr of oxygen alone could make Stella happy, and she could withstand vacuum around 0.01 Torr (the lowest pressure Harry's cheap second-hand mechanical vacuum pump could provide) for at least five minutes. And phoenixes obviously didn't suffer from decompression sickness, for Stella could jump back and forth between the vacuum container and atmosphere without any problem.

By the end, everyone agreed: phoenixes were indeed designed for space missions.

-Therefore, the rumor that phoenix came from the Mirror might be true, and Atlanteans probably did want the good and brave phoenix owners to explore the space. And for thousands of years, wizards on Earth didn't figure this out.

Then, a weird idea came to Harry, and he asked: "Professor Snape, can Stella eat some non-traditional food, such as sulfur, and metals?"

Severus, who had been both amazed by Stella's ability and annoyed by Harry's ideas to "torture" the poor creature, stared at Harry as if he would protect his pet from any further cruelty: "Mr. Potter, although sulfur is a potion ingredient, and some stupid Muggles had considered gold ingestion as a good idea, I wouldn't recommend metals to anyone as food."

Harry and Dad had to explain green sulfur bacteria and iron bacteria metabolism to the wide-eyed potioneer. Finally, Severus reluctantly agreed to let Stella try. Harry briefly considered the possible products of sulfur oxidation, and decided that need to be tried in a closed container with a lot of alkali. However, after Stella reluctantly ate some cutted iron wires, and excreted some red solids - possibly iron(III) oxide, Harry guessed he didn't really need to try sulfur. However, there was indeed another reaction that Harry wanted to try. "Err, Professor Snape, can Stella eat magnesium and burn it in nitrogen?"

The bad-tempered phoenix owner seethed through gritted teeth: "Mr. Potter, you have at most two other experiments to run with Stella today, so plan wisely."

Stella cawed in agreement.

Harry supposed that coming up with various seemingly cruel experiments that you wanted to conduct on a phoenix wasn't the best way to consolidate the loyalty from its owner, and the "two experiments" limit was particularly cruel on a Ravenclaw.

Harry stuttered: "Em, ah, Professor Snape, it's time for dinner now. Could you give me sometime to think?"

The moment Severus and Draco disappeared in Stella's flames, Hermione began giggling and Dad began laughing hard: "Oh, Harry, this - this professor does know you!"

Harry tried to focus on the datasheet, and determined that he was the only sane person in the world at this moment.

Note: Has anyone considered the questions that whether Hagrid's mother was capable of consent, and whether Hagrid's father raped her? And to mate a crab, and a creature with human-level intelligence? Seriously?

Chapter 59: Space Travel Pt XVI, Emotional Choices

I want to thank Dan for beta-ing this chapter.

6:57 pm, August 3rd, 1993

Lucius smirked toward Mad-Eye, as the bad-tempered Auror was sending the three Malfoys a deadly glare while slamming the door of Severus' old office closed. Then, the blond-haired ex-Lord Malfoy began to keenly observe Severus from his back, as his best friend and future Lord applied the usual series of private and protection spells.

Severus' robes were spotted with mud of several different colors, his back was a bit hunched, his shoulders were slack, his usually silky voice was hoarse, while the movements of his wand hand were still precise. And the golden bird of fire on his shoulder looked sad, and somewhat confused.

Lucius shot Narcissa and Draco an inquiring look, but neither his wife nor his son seemed to know the reason for the current situation.

About half an hour ago, Lucius served his second cleaning duty since he entered Nurmengard by washing used meal trays with a rag. The recent change in Nurmengard which required prisoners to serve as house-elves without magic was supposed to teach the inmates some moral lessons, yet Lucius consider this a way to humiliate the prisoners. While the house-elves must be hitting their heads against walls upon their work being taken away, Lucius also overheard some guards complained about the additional work it brought them. If it were any other prison, Lucius might suspect that the prison management wanted to secretly sell some of the house-elves, which had become increasingly expensive these days; however, since this was Nurmengard, Lucius had to suspect something else was at work.

While the ex-Lord Malfoy was plotting how to present this new development to the Boy-Who-Lived, so that the cleaning duty sounded more like a clever scheme, such as a possible escape plan for Lord Grindelwald, instead of a proper form of punishment the Girl-Who-Revived might approve of, Mad-Eye came and hauled Lucius to Hogwarts. This act itself wasn't suspicious, so Lucius gladly threw away the rag, and assumed that the Boy-Who-Lived wanted his service.

However, after arriving at Hogwarts, Lucius was told to change to something appropriate, which was bizarre, for Mad-Eye seemed to gain a twisted sense of satisfaction upon the sight of a Malfoy in prison uniform, and the Boy-Who-Lived and the Girl-Who-Revived thought prison uniform served Lucius justice, while Severus was usually unaware of the status of robes he himself was wearing. A few minutes later, Mad-Eye basically handed Lucius to Severus' care, which was more bizarre. And apparently, his best friend and intended Lord wanted to have a family dinner with all three Malfoys.

It didn't take a Malfoy to figure out something was wrong with Severus.

-And if Severus' problem is severe enough to convince even Mad-Eye that he needed to fetch me…

Lucius became really worried.

The powerful black-haired wizard turned around, and gave a weary smile to Narcissa. "Narcissa, thank you so much for arranging this dinner on such short notice."

Narcissa returned an instinctive polite smile, and said: "Dear Severus, this is the least I can do. "

Even when Lucius was busy trying to figure out the situation, he could hear the lack of subtlety and complaint in his wife's reply. Lucius knew Narcissa was bored in her confinement in Hogwarts, and he knew it was his fault for getting her into all this, yet he couldn't see much he could do to lessen her pain.

As they took their seats, Lucius almost entered a trance as he looked at the woman across the long dining table. He had imagined Narcissa's impeccable smile, elegant demeanor, slim features, beautiful face, and lovely blue eyes many times when he held dinner parties in the Malfoy Manor. At other times, Lucius had imagined her being present in just another room in the huge Manor, such as being still asleep in their bed while he was taking a morning shower, or singing to their little dragon a lullaby before he entered the nursery. Lucius had imagined it so often that he was slowly going mad, and Draco was the only thing that kept him in this hateful world. That was why Lord Malfoy had donated handsomely to the insanity ward in St Mungo's, and had taken the chance of inspecting St Mungo's to visit the Fourth Floor, to study the ravings from the patients with permanent head damages.

Now, Narcissa was alive and breathing, sitting across the table, being the hostess of a Malfoy dinner party, Draco's mother, and most importantly, Lucius' wife, all for real. Lucius felt sourness in his eyes, but quickly kept himself collected in front of their son and guest.

Narcissa had noticed Lucius' gaze, her blue eyes meeting his, and the previous resentment was replaced by sorrow and love.

Lucius wanted to ease her sorrow, to hug her, and to -

The ex-Lord Malfoy quickly stopped this train of thought in front of his son and future Lord, and started pleasant small talk with Severus.

The black-haired wizard, who had definitely noticed the silent emotional exchange, politely offered his opinion on the weather of Midlands England at this time of year.

Lucius found this a bit odd, for Hogwarts was in Scotland, the Malfoy Grange was in Wales, London was in Southeast England, the former USSR was on the Continent, so what was Severus' business in Midlands?

Lucius searched his memory for Severus' connection with Midlands, then remembered that the Prince family home was in Lincolnshire, and the horrible run-down house that Severus grew up in was in a small town near Birmingham.

-Did Severus visit his ancestors' graves before he took on the space mission? This might partially explain his emotional unrest, but why would Mad-Eye consider this sufficient reason to get the Malfoys to dine with Severus?

-More importantly, did Severus talk about the Midlands to indicate something? If so, what is it?

Being a Malfoy who had received the full set of trainings, Lucius had taken an effort to know more about every close kin of this useful ally and friend over the years. As it turned out, Severus didn't have anyone close to him: his mother Eileen Snape nee Prince passed away sometime during Severus' sixth year in Hogwarts, and his despicable muggle father (Tobias or something) died in prison around that time as well. Lucius didn't know much about the muggle side of Severus' other family members, but he knew Severus' maternal grandmother, Virgo Prince nee Lestrange, had passed away when Eileen was in her second year in Hogwarts; and Severus' maternal grandfather, poor old Pius Prince, had a stroke upon the news that his only daughter secretly married a muggle, and stayed in the long-term ward in St Mungo's ever since. According to the visitor log in the Fourth Floor that Lucius had flipped through, Severus visited his grandfather approximately once per year. Back then, Lucius had even wondered, in case Lord Malfoy did end up in the Fourth Floor, how often Draco would visit his mad father, how often would his many friends visit him, and if Severus would pay him a brief courtesy visit while visiting Pius.

-Is it something to do with Pius Prince? Would Severus ask us to visit his grandfather once in a while if his mission fails? Or would he want us to remind the Boy-Who-Lived to think of a way to cure the ones with brain damages?

Lucius knew a good right-hand man should relieve his Lord of worries about his kins, yet visiting one's unresponsive grandfather was not something that you could take upon without being asked, for your Lord might not want to be reminded that his family history was a teaching lesson for all pureblood families on what might happen if your daughters' education failed.

Just as cold appetizer appeared on the table, Lucius' future Lord volunteered an important message: "The schedule for my trip will be advanced to an earlier date."

Lucius' eyes widened. He knew great rituals usually required months or even years of preparation, yet Severus had only had his pheonix for two weeks.

-What happened? Why such urgency? Is there any more danger of the world that I am not aware of?

-Moreover, even if Severus would go to the Moon within the next hour, Mad-Eye is not the kind of person to get me out of prison to meet Severus. There must be something going on here.

Draco's eyes darted to his godfather. His mouth opened as if wanting to ask why, but then closed again. Narcissa exchanged a worried glance with Lucius. And even the snakes and wyverns on the tableclothes started to twist uneasily upon the change of emotions in the dining room.

After some eye exchanges, the Malfoys decided that Lucius should do the talking. The ex-Lord Malfoy allowed appropriate amount of worry and tremble enter his voice, "my dear brother, I wasn't expecting - I wasn't expecting this to be so soon."

Severus regarded him with a bitter and apologetic smile. The black-haired wizard casually tossed the sliced deviled diricawl eggs on his plate, apparently not in a mood to eat. The man's eyes wandered to the crystal glass that was filling itself with blue nettle wine. His right hand put down the fork, and picked up the wine. "Please excuse my ill manners, Mrs. Malfoy. I shouldn't have - Well, thank you so much for this dinner."

Lucius was a bit disappointed by Severus' sudden change of topic, but he and Narcissa had no choice but to assure Severus that he was always welcomed, and preparing this dinner wasn't a burden at all for Narcissa.

Narcissa began to describe how the house-elves in Hogwarts and the ones she brought from Malfoy Manor were in such an ecstasy when they knew they would prepare a formal dinner for all the Malfoys and their most beloved and honored friend, that she had to calm them down a bit.

"Sparky wanted to prepare twenty-one courses for the dinner, while Sweety proposed that we should have twenty-one sweet desserts instead. Unfortunately, I had to break their poor hearts by saying that we wouldn't serve so many courses - let alone desserts - since this would be a family dinner, instead of a state one." Narcissa offered pleasantly.

The overreaction of Sparky, the Malfoy butler house-elf, reminded Lucius of the bitter fact that this was the first formal dinner with both their master and mistress for the first time in eleven years. As for the house-elf named Sweety, Lucius assumed that it was a Hogwarts elf, trained by the old bumblebee Dumbledore, and it proposed twenty-one sweets just to annoy Sparky.

Severus politely smiled, and took a large gulp of nettle wine, which made Lucius worried. The Severus he knew did not indulge with alcohol, and it would be more normal for Severus to deride the Malfoys for the rumored hair-glossing effect of nettles. However, it seemed that the powerful black-haired wizard wanted to get drank.

After Severus had taken several gulps, Lucius decided that he should send the house-elves a signal to serve the next course immediately, so that their guest would at least have something before getting drank. Just as Lucius was about to tap his left pinky finger on the table, he found that Narcissa was already tapping hers. They exchanged a conspiratory smile, and Lucius' heart lightened up despite his worries for his best friend and future Lord.

To Lucius' slight relief, Severus did pick up his spoon, and was about to take some borshch. However, the powerful wizard stared at the beef, cabbage, and beetroot, and the spoon stopped in mid-air for a fraction of a second, and the corner of his mouth twisted a little.

As Severus was taking several courtesy bites, Narcissa gave Lucius an apologetic glance, and Lucius returned her an assuring smile. Lucius knew if he was the host, he wouldn't be so thoughtful as to include something from Russia to compliment his guest; he would probably go with the default bouillabaisse, which Severus would consider pretentious. Now it seemed that Severus wasn't so keen on topics relating to the former USSR.

Draco looked inquiringly at his parents, and was about to take on the responsibility of saving the conversation, yet his words were stopped by a rather strange expression from his godfather.

Severus' black eyes regarded Draco's light blond hair and his young face, and then his eyes went sideways, and studied Lucius' feature in a rather odd way. Then the black-haired wizard spoke: "Narcissa, Lucius, you might have heard of my uncle Severus, whom I was named after."

Lucius nodded. In a society with only approximately ten thousand people, and everyone went to the same school, every pureblood could easily count three generations of most other pureblood families - except the Weasleys, there were simply too many redheads. And since the Princes were a laughstock among purebloods, Lucius did know that Pius and Virgo Prince had a son and a daughter, and the elder son, Severus, died at a very young age, probably before Hogwarts.

"Now as I think of it, the disease that took him away was likely to be measles, or at least my mother probably thought so." Severus' eyes glanced at the perplexed Draco and Lucius, and explained. "Measles is a contagious disease that was once rampant in the muggle world, and it can be dangerous to ones who have not been exposed to it. According to my mother, her elder brother developed high fever and red rashes soon after his first trip to Diagon Alley, and that was why my mother was never allowed to step in any public place before she had to get her wand for Hogwarts."

The black-haired man's lips twisted into a bitter smile.

Although Lucius knew he'd better figure out the implication of such events on his future Lord's psychology (a hateful yet useful muggle word that Lucius learnt recently), his raw instinct wanted to put an air bubble around Draco's head each time he got around the Granger girl.

-Those dirty muggles and mudbloods!

"I remember my mother used to take me to muggle hospitals to get vaccine shots when I was very young. And when I was approximately nine years old, although money was tight, and I'd already been vaccinated against measles when I was younger, my mother still dragged me to a private muggle hospital to receive an advanced measles vaccine that had not yet been covered by NHS." Severus' voice was mournful, and black eyes wandered to the ceiling, and into the past.

Although Lucius could tell Severus recounted an emotional event, the pureblood wizard had no idea of several important concepts.

-What is a vaccine shot? Why is it related to measles? And what is NHS?

Narcissa took in an involuntary breath, and she looked all of a sudden ashamed of herself. "Severus, I am so sorry to hear that. And you mean Draco should -"

"I mean all of you." Severus replied.

Lucius was more perplexed than before. And from the look on Draco's face, the boy was trying hard to remember something.

As cuisses de grenouille replaced soup on the table, the half-blood wizard began to explain vaccines to his best friend and godson, and why many contagious diseases were no longer serious threats in the muggle society.

"Because of vaccines, the prevalences of many potentially dangerous diseases are quite low among first- and second-world muggles. Vaccines for chickenpox were invented recently, and I've gotten one shot last year, for I suspect dragon pox might be a variant of the muggle disease chickenpox, - the symptoms are similar, and both of them are more dangerous for adults than children. " Severus concluded his explanation with a significant look toward Lucius and Draco.

Lucius' eyes widened in disbelief.

-Did Severus mean that the dirty muggles are not only spreading dangerous diseases that kill pureblood wizards, but they are also inventing things that could prevent diseases, and potentially save wizards?

-If only muggles had invented chickenpox vaccine earlier...

Lucius remembered his father, Lord Abraxas Malfoy, in his last days: his fair skin became green, green-and-purple bumps erupted everywhere, his hair fell out, the high fever and uncontrollable cough, bleeding problems…

Then Lucius realized, even if the muggles had invented the chickenpox vaccine before his father was infected, the Malfoys most likely wouldn't take the vaccine shots as Severus - and possibly many other mudbloods and half-bloods - did.

"Comrade Shakhov used to require all wizarding children in Russia to receive muggle vaccines before entering magical school, and it didn't seem to have much negative impact on the health of wizarding children." Severus said meaningfully to Draco and Lucius.

Lucius pondered on this. His instinct told him not to trust the dirty muggles, however Severus had little reason to lie about something that a whole nation did, and it rang a tone of the kind of incredible yet true things in Potter's books.

-Moreover, Narcissa knows about this vaccine thing, and she thinks that she should have Draco take it. Therefore, it is likely that vaccine is a good thing in the muggle world. As for the NHS thing, it sounded like it has something to do with money, which isn't a problem for the Malfoys.

-Although the Stone can heal most diseases, the "haem-something type B"Severus talked about sounded like a disease that can hurt the brain, which the Stone cannot cure.

"That sounds like an excellent idea!" Lucius forced himself to smile, and told himself that he was only being pragmatic as all Malfoys should, and not admitting that muggles could be better than wizards in some very small and very specific field of healing.

"Oh, dear Severus, Draco is so lucky to have you as his godfather." Narcissa said sincerely.

Severus smiled a bit smugly despite his generally gloomy mood.

Lucius was glad to see that Severus still enjoyed sincere praises, so he was about to shower his best friend with them.

However, Severus' trail of thoughts were more unpredictable than usual, as the man said: "Our dear Headmistress Minerva McGonagall is committing a slow suicide by trying to be the Headmistress and the Transfiguration Professor at the same time, among all other things. She might have collapsed if not for the Stone. I wonder, if she might need assistance."

It took Lucius a moment to make the connections: Severus is indicating that Narcissa should be the one to propose the idea that all British witches and wizards should take muggle vaccines, as a gesture of submission in front of the Boy-Who-Lived. And Narcissa would become a player on the board for her own right.

This scheme was certainly clever, and the idea that everyone should get vaccinated was definitely something that a witch who was forced to spend eleven years in the muggle world could propose, yet it contradicted Lucius' instinct on so many levels that he couldn't point out all of them.

Being pragmatic and taking advantages of the rare good things muggles produced was one thing, yet letting everyone know was completely another matter. The Malfoys had served muggle royalties for gold and land before, and there was even a muggle queen who wanted to marry the first Lucius, yet nobody in the wizarding world needed to know about it - so long as they were ignorant of the amount of gold and silver the muggle nobility could offer, the Malfoys were without competition in this regard. However, if everyone knew the good things muggles produced, the Malfoys wouldn't have much advantage over other wizards.

-However, since the Boy-Who-Lived and the Girl-Who-Revived were raised in the muggle world, they should know the vaccine thing already. But why didn't they propose it?

And Lucius asked as such.

The half-blood wizard answered sardonically: "Vaccines are so common in the muggle world, that our beloved Lord and Lady probably don't know that wizards don't have them, for I, a half-blood, wasn't fully aware of this until several years after becoming Head of Slytherin. However, at that time, I wasn't - let's say, I wasn't in a position that could easily propose such an idea."

-And Severus probably didn't care enough for anyone in the wizarding world. Otherwise, he could simply leave some indications in the Muggle Studies Professor's mind. Not until Draco became his godson.

Lucius' eyes wandered to his beloved dragon, and found that Draco was looking at his mother. Lucius turned his gaze to his wife, and saw that her hands were slightly tight on the utensils, and her neck was a bit too straight.

-She is nervous about - herself? Or about my reactions?

Before Lucius joined the Death Eaters, they had made a conscious decision that Lucius should be the only one to risk his life, and Narcissa should play the role of a good pureblood wife. However, things had changed. The game nowadays was more complex and dangerous than any Malfoy had played in the past one thousand years, and becoming a player meant danger. Most parts of Lucius were exalted by such a challenge, yet a small part of him was intimidated and always wanted to flee. It was one thing to risk yourself, it was completely another matter that someone you loved, lost, and recently returned would risk her life…

Lucius' hands whitened on his knife and fork. In his mind, a respectable pureblood witch should raise children, run business, manipulate Wizengamot, but not become a lunatic like Bellatrix.

But our plan didn't work so well in the previous war. Lucius ruefully remembered. Maybe it would be better to let Narcissa to become a player without becoming Bellatrix.

The idea that Narcissa wouldn't be in the first line of fire calmed Lucius a little.

In another corner, some dark intuition told the pureblood patriarch that if Narcissa were to become a player in her own right, she might drift away from him.

-But she is in pain. One Malfoy is more than enough for imprisonment, and there is no need for two.

Lucius swallowed down his bitterness, gave Narcissa an encouraging smile, and turned to Severus: "My dear Severus, I always pride myself with my vocabulary, yet I can hardly find words to describe your cunning, and more importantly, to properly thank you for your love and kindness."

Just as Lucius began to compliment Severus that he was more loyal to his family and friends than Lady Hufflepuff, and was probably more cunning than Lord Slytherin himself, the ex-Head of Slytherin suddenly nervously coughed, his black-eyes bewildered for a second, and then began to share his impression of the young Petunia Evans, his general knowledge on muggle professors and dentists, and the politics among Hogwarts staff.

Lucius listened, and slowly and sadly realized what Severus was doing: he is arranging for the Malfoys in case he wouldn't come back. He is indeed the best and most loyal friend that I have ever had, and probably will ever have.

The grim possibility of losing Severus saddened Lucius. It wasn't quite in the same way as when Lucius watched black cat flu taking away his mother, and later dragon pox his father, but it became close. Both diseases were potentially fatal, but the majority of patients were eventually cured. Lucius had experienced the hope, the anxiety, the fanatic search for any healing magic, the devastation, and the final departure - no, not final departure, the cursed Boy-Who-Lived would probably figure out a way to bring everyone back.

Lucius managed a smile on his face, and continued listening to his dear friend.

During one course followed by another, Severus shared his knowledge on the politics among Hogwarts staff, and important matters relating to the student body during his tenure in Hogwarts, in the meanwhile taking more alcohol than he usually did.

Although Lucius usually wanted his guests to loosen up and be more talkative after a few drinks, the ex-Lord Malfoy began to sense that he might not want to know what Severus was really holding back. He had to signal the house-elves to switch the beverages to ones containing less alcohol.

-Or is he just waiting for an opportunity to tell me something?

Whatever it was, Lucius guessed it wasn't good.

And when dessert was on the table, Severus stopped his revelation of Professor Sinistra, and a twisted smile appeared on the corner of his lips. The black-haired man sighed, and said: "Narcissa, may I borrow your husband for a few hours?"

-I am to stay for the night?!

Lucius felt a wave of rejoicing, even though part of his brain was quite aware of the fact the following few hours probably would not be easy, while another part of him reminded that it must have costed Severus a lot to let the paranoid Auror to allow Lucius to stay for the night.

After a few bites of blancmange, Severus thanked Narcissa again, and then retreated to the study with Lucius.

Before Lucius could speak, Severus ordered a bottle of firewhisky from house-elves, and poured two glasses. "I am sorry, Lucius, but I may need some alcohol now."

Stella looked at her master disapprovingly, yet remained silent.

After the black-hair potioneer took a large gulp of alcohol, he drew out three bottles of green potions, and put them on the large oaken table ornamented with snakes and wyverns. "Antidote for alcohol, pour one down my throat in case you consider it necessary."

This really sounded ominous.

Severus sat down in one of the comfortable leather chairs, cleared his throat, his usually silky voice hoarse and shaky: "Lucius, there is something that I want to ask of you. You may decide whether you would like to do it or not after hearing the whole story. I - I don't know where to start, so I'll start with what Mad-Eye and the Boy-Who-Lived told me this afternoon."

Then, Severus told his best friend about the old photo of Lord Rasputin, Mad-Eye's theory, and the digging of his own ancestors' graves this afternoon.

"I've sent hair from my parents, all my four grandparents, and all their supposed parents that I could find, to a muggle lab to test for their kinship." Severus' black eyes glistened with traces of water, his voice became blurry as he finished the full bottle of firewhisky. And his hand went to the first bottle of antidote for alcohol without Lucius' suggestion.

The pureblood wizard stared at the copies of magical and muggle photos: Lord Rasputin after his death, Tobias Snape, Nicolas Snape, Eileen Prince, and Virgo Lestrange. The faces were quite self-evident.

There was indeed a rumor among purebloods with certain traditions, that making horcruxes would bring misfortune to one's offsprings, yet Lucius never thought the misfortune would come at such a literal sense. Then Lucius got it in absolute horror: this must be the second level of horcruxes, that you have to literally curse your offsprings, to let them produce your new body.

Severus observed the horrified expression, and said: "So you must have realized."

"Yes, the curse of horcrux for one's offsprings is literally so." The blond wizard murmured.

"What?" Severus asked in surprise.

And then the black-haired wizard straightened up, drank down the second bottle of antidote for alcohol in one gulp. "I'm such a utterly self-centered fool! I need to tell -"

"Oh, well, Mad-Eye must have been checking on this already."Severus slowly relaxed back down the chair, put one hand over his face, and his voice tired: "And I have just proved how slow I am."

-Err, Severus didn't think of this? And what did Severus actual think of?

-The fact that he should avoid touching any horcrux? But that's pretty straight-forward without knowledge of the additional curse.

-The cause of family tragedy? But Severus has told me so in plain words.

Then Lucius realized, and it terrorized him on another level: the curse encourages incest, and -

At this point, Lucius couldn't even tell if measles taking away Severus Prince's life before the boy attended Hogwarts was a bad thing. Lucius didn't really want to ponder on what relationship Severus Prince might have with his younger sister and/or his mother if the boy entered puberty.

-Severus doesn't seem to have an improper relationship with his mother, though. But the existence of Tobias might explain this.

-Also, Severus probably shouldn't run all over the former USSR at this time. And that's why the Boy-Who-Lived and Severus decided that the launch date should be advanced.

The black-haired wizard looked rather embarrassed, and his black-eyes were focusing on a snake on the oaken table, not on Lucius, as he said: "I know what I am asking may put you in a rather difficult position, but - before I figure out how to get rid of the curse, could you try to stop me if it seems like I - I want to lay down with some female?"

-Err…

There was pleading in Severus' voice: "I know that process might just take less than an hour, probably before anybody would have the chance to intervene. Therefore, if I am dumb enough and weak enough to procreate anyway, under the influence of the curse or no, could you please be my child's godfather, and prevent me from meeting my daughter, or prevent my child's mother from meeting her son?"

Lucius didn't know any previous Malfoy had been told by their Lords to stop them from gaining certain pleasures. He should say yes and do this for his best friend, because friends should stop friends from committing unspeakable crimes of this nature; but saying yes might also mean to seriously offend his Lord at a time when the said powerful Lord might not be reasonable at all.

Lucius knew Severus was expecting his answer, most likely in Parseltongue, and that was an answer that Lucius could not give lightly. Saying yes would mean that he had to rebel against his powerful Lord and face the potentially lethal ramifications, but saying no would mean he had to watch his best friend committ horrible crimes and falling forever into self-loathing.

Severus sighed. "Lucius, I am sorry for asking so much of you. I would block your memory, and -"

The black-haired man hesitated.

-No, Severus would go to Mad-Eye Moody or the Boy-Who-Lived for this request. And Mad-Eye would just gladly castrate Severus, and curse him with who-knows-what!

-Wait, Mad-Eye would request Severus to sacrifice his male part, and probably his sexual identity in a ritual!

"I will try my besst to sstop ssuch tragedy from happening or becoming worsse." hissed Lucius, and he added. "Pleasse try not to kill me."